<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[TeamMood's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.teammood.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.teammood.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-21T21:48:17+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.teammood.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[TeamMood]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the niko-niko ?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-21T21:57:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Niko-niko calendar is an Agile practice which aims to detect patterns of change of mood of a team over time.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://blog.teammood.com/images/posts/niko-niko.jpg" title="An example of Niko-niko calendar" ></p>

<p>The technic is very easy: at the end of the day, each team member paste a sticker on a calendar to tell if he had a good day at work.</p>

<p>In other word, you probably ever went back to home from work and feel that you had a bad day, or you did not feel &#8220;productive&#8221;. That&#8217;s a red sticker.</p>

<p>After some time, you&#8217;ll see some color being dominant, it will give an insight of the mood of the team.</p>

<p>It is a good idea to take a look at the Niko-niko calendar during the Agile retrospective.</p>

<p>It is not exact science, it is just a simple tool to get some more informations about the team.</p>

<p>The Niko-niko calendar is also know as &#8220;happiness index&#8221;. Also note that &#8220;niko&#8221; means &#8220;smile&#8221; in the japanese language.</p>

<p>The first mention of the Niko-niko calendar is from an <a href="http://www.geocities.jp/nikonikocalendar/index_en.html" target="_blank">article from Akinori SAKATA in 2006</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great tool to polish your idea]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/19/great-tool-to-polish-your-idea/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-19T19:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/19/great-tool-to-polish-your-idea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you search the Web for resources about entrepreneurship, (lean)startup and so on, you&#8217;ll find a lot of articles and advices, but it is very hard to know how to begin, and what&#8217;s could be your next move.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t remember how I get on this when I was doing some research for my <a href="http://teammood.com">TeamMood project</a>, but I found an awesome gold nugget : <a href="http://startitup.co">StartitUp</a></p>

<p><a href="http://startitup.co"><img class="center" src="http://blog.teammood.com/images/posts/startitup.png" title="" ></a></p>

<p>Based on the Lean Startup, it helps me lot with valuable advices, and a lot of articles containing several samples.</p>

<p>It is very simple to use : you go through the step by step guide, answer some questions about your idea/team/competition etc… and it progressively builds your Lean Canvas and helps you to structure your mind.</p>

<p>Also note that these guys are expecting a lot of feedback, and they are super reactive.</p>

<p>So if you have an idea, and you don&#8217;t know where to start, go on <a href="http://startitup.co">StartitUp</a> !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Twitter effect]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/18/the-twitter-effect/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-18T15:23:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/18/the-twitter-effect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At last, I finally &#8220;officially&#8221; launched the TeamMood project by using two announce ments through Twitter, this is the one in English (another one was made in French):</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="fr"><p>Guys, I&#8217;m launching my first side-project !! <a href="http://t.co/9h4lyIIMtc" title="http://teammood.com">teammood.com</a>, feel free to share the love ;-) <a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23teammood">#teammood</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23nikoniko">#nikoniko</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/search/%23happy">#happy</a></p>&mdash; Nicolas Deverge (@ndeverge) <a href="https://twitter.com/ndeverge/status/324860646296539136">18 avril 2013</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://blog.teammood.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>So far so good, in just hour, I had 29 people who registred by giving their email for about 179 unique visitors.</p>

<p>And I also received many positive feedbacks from some people.</p>

<p>I think that my first MVP has quite a good result, so now, I have to keep on the adventure !!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Idea]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/03/31/the-idea/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-31T15:07:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/03/31/the-idea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a while since I wanted to build a project of my own. On a daily basis, I give advices to IT companies about technologies, methodologies and strategies to build awesome products. And now it is my turn !</p>

<p>So I finally took the time to build my first side project: <a href="http://teammood.com" class="teammood">TeamMood</a> !</p>

<p><a href="http://teammood.com"><img class="center" src="http://blog.teammood.com/images/posts/coming-soon.png" title="" ></a></p>

<p>I will not explain what the project is about in this post, I prefer to let you discover the idea through the very first MVP which is a simple &#8221;<a href="http://teammood.com">coming soon</a>&#8221; page and let you give me a lot of <a href="mailto:hello@teammood.com">feedback</a>.</p>

<p>Basically, the idea scratched me since many months because I feel that it can bring a lot in some companies that I work with. But it took me a lot of time before starting to build something, probably because I thought that if I begin to do this, I&#8217;d have to pull it to the end, ie some kind of commitment.</p>

<p>And yes, I use LeanStartup to explore the idea, because I don&#8217;t know if it will be a good one and if people will be interested. So let&#8217;s learn with this first MVP and we&#8217;ll see :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
