<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TeamMood&#39;s Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.teammood.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://blog.teammood.com/</link>
    <description>Some words about feeling good at work.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 13:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Encourage Work-Life Balance at Work</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2019/04/16/how-to-encourage-work-life-balance-at-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2019/04/16/how-to-encourage-work-life-balance-at-work.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stress and burnout have become an increasing phenomenon worldwide over the last decade. According to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virgin.com/disruptors/infographic-how-stressed-are-uk-employees&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouGov survey&lt;/a&gt;, 51% of full-time UK employees said they have experienced anxiety or burnout in their current job. In France, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ringover.com/en/blog/burnout-the-epidemic-of-the-century&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;53% of employees and 68% of managers find their job too stressful&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation seems contradictory with the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;happy employees are more productive&lt;/a&gt; than unhappy ones. If someone’s health is his or her own responsibility, employers have an important part to play in their employees’ well-being. Here are &lt;strong&gt;7 policies you can implement to help your team members achieve work-life balance&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;implementing-a-flexible-work-schedule-policy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Implementing a flexible work schedule policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every employee works differently, some intrinsically tend to concentrate better in the morning, others are more productive at night. Setting up a fixed work schedule forces team members to adapt their natural cycle to the company, creating stress in their own body up to a feeling of imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents may need to leave early from work in order to fetch their kids from daycare or school. Other collaborators may want to go play squash during their lunch break or attend a yoga session after work. Whatever their reason, favoring a flexible work schedule will help your employees better respect their own needs. As a result, they will feel more relaxed at work, increasing their focus and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;encouraging-work-life-balance-flexible-work-scheduleuploadsteammood-work-life-balance-1png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/teammood-work-life-balance-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Encouraging work-life balance: Flexible work schedule&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;offering-partial-or-full-remote-working-to-your-employees&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Offering partial or full remote working to your employees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going every day to the office makes employees spend time telecommuting. Depending on where they live, the number of hours wasted can sum up absurdly at the end of the year. And the stress generated by the hours spent behind the wheel stuck in traffic is highly unproductive too. Likewise, some employees may decide to go and work in a big city in order to get a job, while dreaming to live on the opposite side of the country, or even abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An increasing number of employees favor flexibility at work – especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/02/managers-do-you-know-how-to-work-with-millennials.html&quot;&gt;millennials&lt;/a&gt;. Letting your employees decide where they want to work greatly participates in helping them find their own balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/teammood-work-life-balance-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Encouraging work-life balance: remote working&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;favoring-lunch-and-coffee-breaks&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Favoring lunch and coffee breaks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some managers and hard workers still consider breaks as time wasted on their work day. On the contrary! Our brain works like a muscle: it needs training, but also resting and key nutrients, including oxygen and water. You can’t just make it operate at full capacity for hours without taking a break. At some point, your productivity and creativity will inevitably decrease, losing the benefits of the few minutes you “saved” earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.buffer.com/science-taking-breaks-at-work/&quot;&gt;Courtney Seiter from Buffer&lt;/a&gt;, breaks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;keep us from getting bored, thus increase our focus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;help us retain information and make connections – which automatically increases our creativity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give us the opportunity to reevaluate our goals and reorder our priorities of the day/week/year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose your own way to take a break: going for lunch with your colleagues, exercising, going some meditation, taking a quick nap after lunch, reading a book… The key is to listen to your body and look after yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/teammood-work-life-balance-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Encouraging work-life balance: lunch and coffee breaks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-a-culture-of-efficiency-rather-than-workload&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Setting up a culture of efficiency rather than workload&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you rather see your employees work long hours but wasting time throughout the day, or be focused, and leave early from the office? One can hardly be efficient for 10 or 12 hours in a row. Plus we all have different capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incentivizing your team members to producing great results rather than working long hours will motivate them to get the job done and use their free time as they wish. It’s a win-win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/teammood-work-life-balance-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Encouraging work-life balance: Efficiency rather than workload&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;freeing-up-your-holiday-policy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Freeing up your holiday policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offering paid time off is crucial to let your employees rest, take their mind off work, recharge their batteries. This essential break gives a true breath that lulls them into a state of serenity before jumping back in their daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Offering a generous vacation policy is one of the many ways you can show your employees gratitude. And if you want to go a step further, you can follow ZenPayroll example and opt for an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themuse.com/advice/unlimited-vacation-policy-what-you-should-know&quot;&gt;unlimited vacation policy&lt;/a&gt;. The huge plus? &lt;em&gt;“It helps build an ownership mentality”&lt;/em&gt; according to Joshua Reeves, their CEO and co-founder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful though, when offered unlimited vacations, some employees may end up taking fewer days off. At Basecamp, to counter this perverse effect, employees are offered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.fr/us/basecamp-ceo-says-hes-running-out-of-perks-2017-6&quot;&gt;financial package to go on holidays&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/teammood-work-life-balance-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Encouraging work-life balance: Free up your holiday policy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;helping-new-parents&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Helping new parents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you believe that in the 21st century, offering paternity leave is still not obvious for a majority of companies? The capitalist model tends to forget that a good part of the world’s equilibrium is based on free “work”: having kids and raising them. Take it away and the whole economy collapses, more surely than if a war breaks out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New parents bear this incredible responsibility in addition to their work. And everything that their company can implement to ease their job will make their lives a little bit smoother: offering flexible schedules, extending paternity leave, creating a daycare center for the company or booking some spots in an exterior structure… Your employees will definitely feel grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/teammood-work-life-balance-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Encouraging work-life balance: Helping new parents&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;encouraging-sports-activities-and-meditation&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Encouraging sports activities and meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the risks of working long hours is to prevent yourself from getting enough exercise. Indeed, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.bufferapp.com/why-exercising-makes-us-happier&quot;&gt;activities can make you happier, give you more energy and help you gain focus&lt;/a&gt;. By offering flexible working hours, dedicating a room for working out, sponsoring a gym membership, or creating a small bathroom to take a shower after a run at lunchtime, you can encourage your employees to take the time to exercise, for the sake of their mental and physical health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, meditation has proven highly beneficial to relax your brain and lower stress. If your office has an empty room, you can consider turning it into a meditation room that your employees can use throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/teammood-work-life-balance-7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Encouraging work-life balance: sport activities and meditation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, all this will have no impact if you don’t set the example yourself. Change needs to come from the leadership, translated into values and policies, and implemented at every level of the company. Work-life balance must be at the core of your company if you want it to truly improve the wellbeing of your employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-you-want-to-improve-your-teams-work-life-balance-drop-us-a-note-at-helloteammoodcommailtohelloteammoodcom-and-talk-to-our-experts&quot;&gt;Do you want to improve your team’s work-life balance? Drop us a note at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#109;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#109;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt; and talk to our experts.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why doing Team Health Checks?</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2019/03/29/why-doing-team-health-checks.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2019/03/29/why-doing-team-health-checks.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Great success and achievements do not come overnight, and are rarely the result of a person alone, but rather by a group of individuals what we commonly call a “team”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/proverb-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;If you want to go fast, go alone. If you want to go far, go together&quot; title=&quot;If you want to go fast, go alone. If you want to go far, go together&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to work together, as a true team, is far better than the expertise of each individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-makes-a-team-great&quot;&gt;But what makes a team great?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, Google did &lt;a href=&quot;https://rework.withgoogle.com/blog/five-keys-to-a-successful-google-team/&quot;&gt;its own research&lt;/a&gt; and found these 5 characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Psychological safety: Can we take risks on this team without feeling insecure or embarrassed?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dependability: Can we count on each other to do high-quality work on time?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Structure &amp;amp; clarity: Are goals, roles, and execution plans on our team clear?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meaning of work: Are we working on something that is personally important for each of us?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Impact of work: Do we fundamentally believe that the work we’re doing matters?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Team Health Check&lt;/strong&gt; is a great way to take the temperature of a team. And that’s a starting point for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;goals-of-a-team-health-check&quot;&gt;Goals of a Team Health Check&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By doing regular checks, teams should be able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increase trust and psychological safety within the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have better relationships between teammates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a culture of constructive criticism and feedback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raise issues and fix them quickly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share their feelings more easily and frequently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/meditation-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Keep your team zen thanks to regular Team Health Checks&quot; title=&quot;Keep your team zen thanks to regular Team Health Checks&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-do-a-team-health-check&quot;&gt;How to do a Team Health Check&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to run a Team Health Check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-a-niko-niko-calendar&quot;&gt;Use a Niko-Niko Calendar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/07/24/evaluating-your-teams-health-with-the-niko-niko-calendar.html&quot;&gt;Niko-Niko Calendar&lt;/a&gt; is a simple calendar with everybody’s name on it. At the end of the day, each team member is invited to share their mood of the day, sticking smilies happy :-), straight :-, or frowning :-( or color stickers on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-an-emotional-seismograph-with-the-team&quot;&gt;Create an Emotional Seismograph with the team&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During, one of your retrospectives, try the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/10/30/the-emotional-seismograph-a-fun-and-effective-retrospective-format.html&quot;&gt;Emotional Seismograph&lt;/a&gt; format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an easy and fun way to get an overview of your team health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;run-team-health-check-like-spotify&quot;&gt;Run Team Health Check like Spotify&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Team Health Check has been popularized by Spotify with their &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.spotify.com/2014/09/16/squad-health-check-model/&quot;&gt;Squad Health Check model&lt;/a&gt;, where people are asked to score 11 different areas (Easy to release, Suitable process, Tech quality, Value, Speed, Mission, Fun, Learning, Support, Pawns or players) on three levels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;green: good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;yellow: some problems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;red: really bad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;suggest-improvements-from-a-team-health-check&quot;&gt;Suggest improvements from a Team Health Check&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As proposed by Aaron Gallagher from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/team-temp-aka-health-check-aaron-gallagher/&quot;&gt;his article about Team Health Check&lt;/a&gt;, you can combine a Team Health Check with a Perfection Game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“[During a Perfection Game], people have to rate the value that they received on a scale from 1 to 10, based on how much value they think they could add themselves by improving the product or service. For example, when there is nothing that they think they can improve, they should rate with a 10. If they think that they could make it twice as valuable, they should give it a 5.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(…)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If somebody rates the value as 5, (s)he will have to provide suggestions on how to make it a 10. People can only withhold points if they provide suggestions to improve it.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;From Ben Linders, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.benlinders.com/2014/getting-feedback-with-the-perfection-game/&quot;&gt;https://www.benlinders.com/2014/getting-feedback-with-the-perfection-game/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting from a Team Health Check, Aaron proposes to think about what we could do so that people would feel better in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-turn&quot;&gt;Your turn!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still amazed by the fact that however simple the concept of Team Health Check is, it’s still rarely used by team leaders. So, start now with your first Team Health Check, and if you fall in love with it, use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt; to do it on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/dance-the-music-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Run your first Team Health Check, and be amazed!&quot; title=&quot;Run your first Team Health Check, and be amazed!&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dare Benevolent Leadership!</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2019/03/05/dare-benevolent-leadership.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2019/03/05/dare-benevolent-leadership.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is a translation of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/osez-le-management-bienveillant-julien-rigoulay/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;French article&lt;/a&gt;, written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/julienrigoulay/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Julien Rigoulay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Benevolent leadership is a concept at the heart of discussions in companies that want to innovate and boost productivity. Initially seen as naive or just a trend following on from the humanist movement, benevolence in the workplace is now considered a “strong lever” for attracting employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;With the massive retirement of the baby boom generation, wage portage, and young executives increasingly attracted by positions abroad, the current context forces companies to review their management style. Indeed, in order to recruit reliable and motivated employees, companies must adopt a different, more ethical and attractive policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;This is where benevolence comes into play: it breaks the hierarchical structure that reflects aggressive practices in the corporate world. When each individual feels at ease in their work environment, they become more productive and feel more involved. But before we go any further, let’s take a closer look at this concept to make it really beneficial for your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot; id=&quot;benevolent-leadership-what-is-it-exactly&quot;&gt;Benevolent leadership, what is it exactly?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;To boil it right down, here are the main points that make the difference in a benevolently-managed company:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot; id=&quot;inviting-collaborators-to-take-part-in-major-decisions&quot;&gt;Inviting collaborators to take part in major decisions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;When managers promote discussion around major decisions within their company, they empower their team members. This is an effective strategy to make employees feel more involved. Indeed, when each individual feels that they are contributing to the company’s development, it creates attachment. Note that management itself doesn’t have to be collaborative, but discussion is always important before making any major decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot; id=&quot;adopting-a-caring-attitude-and-always-being-attentive&quot;&gt;Adopting a caring attitude and always being attentive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;A manager who’s not afraid to smile is like a breath of fresh air in the workplace. Not only does it make team members more relaxed, but it also makes them &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/en/get-feedback/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;more likely to share crucial information should a problem arise&lt;/a&gt;, helping to reach a resolution more quickly. Indeed, a stern-faced manager can put employees off from sharing their thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;It’s also vital for managers to have good listening skills. Not only is the information provided by the teams always important for making good decisions, but their active participation also motivates them. When a manager pays attention and acts on the recommendations of a team member, the latter will feel more motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot; id=&quot;a-benevolent-manager-but-no-cronyism&quot;&gt;A benevolent manager, but no “cronyism”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;To be a good manager, you have to treat all your employees equally. Indeed, benevolence does not mean being “buddies” with everyone. We must not lose sight of the ultimate aim: to serve the interests of the company. To achieve this, the manager must manage team members equally without playing favourites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot; id=&quot;recognizing-that-mistakes-happen-and-promoting-communication&quot;&gt;Recognizing that mistakes happen and promoting communication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Employees learn and forge themselves in part by making mistakes. A benevolent manager must accept that to err is human and recognize that people are bound to mess up from time to time. This kind of mindset fosters confidence within a team by taking the pressure off and promoting a good atmosphere at work. However, benevolence does not mean that there are no consequences, but they must be proportional to the mistake made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Communication plays a vital role in benevolent management. A manager with strong communication skills can share information or announce decisions with ease. For example, if salary increases are to reflect individual performance, this detail must be communicated from the beginning. That being said, it will be easier for the manager to explain if some team members don’t get an increase. However, bad news must always be announced with respect and finesse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot; id=&quot;how-to-manage-with-kindness&quot;&gt;How to manage with kindness?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Although the concept of benevolent leadership is on the lips of business leaders and heads of department everywhere, it seems to be little more than a good intention. Indeed, most who try to implement it tend to forget that it requires a real implementation plan. A profound change must be made in order to get results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Company leaders must define a new management approach, possibly with the help of a specialized coach. The organization must also evolve to promote benevolence within the company while respecting the specificities of the company. A dynamic and solid balance must be created and maintained within a positive environment that promotes efficiency and energy. Here are some recommendations that will help you achieve a genuine transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot; id=&quot;the-process-must-be-global&quot;&gt;The process must be global&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;The project must come from the top of the hierarchy and encompass each and every one of the company’s departments and teams. Indeed, if benevolent management is practiced by only one manager, it won’t affect the whole organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Benevolence needs to be more than just a Human Resources Department project. It must become a source of motivation for each individual. Employees need to be involved and motivated to help managers move forward, especially in times of crisis. Indeed, when teams are loyal, there is less turnover: the presence of each individual contributes to the smooth overall running of the company and boosts productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot; id=&quot;every-employee-counts&quot;&gt;Every employee counts &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;The concept of corporate benevolence implies that a radically individual-oriented policy be established. Each person must feel useful and special. The professional and personal lives of every team member matters. Some leaders think that giving more time to the personal life of an employee will make him or her less productive. On the contrary! If managers give more importance to employees’ personal life and well-being, they will be more productive. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;Fostering this perspective requires managers who know how to listen. When an employee makes an effort, they must be recognized for their true value. This encourages them to be more creative and to feel more involved in the company life, which automatically fosters a feeling of belonging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.shrm.org/resourcesandtools/hr-topics/talent-acquisition/pages/candidates-choose-jobs-company-culture.aspx&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;ust=1551799259820000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNE0IoSYdUT4c6-ZTb9PW72EXdbyow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A recent study&lt;/a&gt; revealed that over the next decade, it’s the candidates who will choose which company they want to work for rather than the other way around. Managers will have to set up a recruitment system that attracts the profiles they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Many changes have to be made before benevolent leadership can become more than just a good intention. The outdated practices of previous generations will no longer suffice. If companies fail to adapt their approach, productivity will decline. Balance has become all important in the employee-company relationship: managers will have to step up their efforts to implement benevolence if they want to grow company profits!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;present-before-paste&quot;&gt;What about you, have you taken the plunge? Share your experience in the comments section below!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hire for Culture Fit, Not Competencies</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2019/02/19/hire-for-culture-fit-not-competencies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2019/02/19/hire-for-culture-fit-not-competencies.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the relentlessly competitive global climate, the key to success in business isn’t what you do but how you do it. Providing the best product or service isn’t enough – you need to differentiate yourself from the competition at team, department and company level. But how? That’s where your company culture can make all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aligning-your-culture-and-brand&quot;&gt;Aligning your culture and brand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A strong, differentiated company culture contributes to a strong, differentiated brand that will attract both customers and employees. Examples vary from one company to the next: offering generous employee benefits such as free drinks at Starbucks, encouraging employees to disagree with their managers at Amazon, empowering employees to be their own boss at Zappos, letting people set their own hours at Patagonia, unlimited vacation or no tracking policy at Netflix…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s obvious that if you want to win the battle for customers, your culture and brand need to be aligned and driven by a common purpose and set of values. And it all starts with recruitment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reasons-you-should-hire-for-culture-fit-over-skill-set&quot;&gt;4 reasons you should hire for culture fit over skill set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lower-turnover&quot;&gt;Lower turnover&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably want to be surrounded by the best – that’s par for the course. But “the best” doesn’t necessarily mean “the most qualified” or “the candidate with the best degree”. In fact, hiring top performers that don’t fit your company culture is a recipe for unhappy employees that won’t adjust to your organization or get along with their teammates. In the end, they will stagnate in their position until they find a better one elsewhere. This kind of bad fit is the reason why &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/danschawbel/2012/01/23/89-of-new-hires-fail-because-of-their-attitude/#56acdf3f137a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;50% of new hires fail in the first 18 months&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-feeling-of-belonging&quot;&gt;A feeling of belonging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrating a highly qualified person who doesn’t fit your company culture will be more challenging than making a success of hiring a  good match for your company culture with a more average skill set. They will always feel like outsiders and integrating them will represent a considerable challenge. On the other hand, fitting in with your company culture gives your employees a feeling of belonging, thereby increasing their loyalty to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-smarter-bet-in-the-long-run&quot;&gt;A smarter bet in the long run&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KUWn_TJTrnU&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;growth versus fixed mindset model&lt;/a&gt;, put forth by psychologist Carol Dweck? It basically states that education should value effort over result in order to help us enjoy the process of learning about new topics and acquiring new skills. Giving too much importance to your employees’ skill set or achievements on the day you recruit them may not encourage them to be curious and explore new areas in the future. In our rapidly changing business landscape, it won’t be long before they start lagging behind. Choosing a candidate for his or her potential instead is the smarter bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increased-collaboration&quot;&gt;Increased collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring a highly qualified person who doesn’t fit with your company culture can jeopardize the whole company’s equilibrium. Indeed, “unity is strength” is only valid when people actually want to work together. Team members that share the same values will get along better, improving team spirit and overall collaboration inside the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring for culture fit involves defining your company, department or team culture first: the values, implicit rules, and interactions among employees that differentiate your tribe from any other organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;❗Be careful not to confuse the lack of diversity with culture fit. Diversity is vital to your company’s ability to innovate and adapt to an ever-evolving environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you defined your company/department/team culture? Do you leverage it in your hiring process? Tell us in the comments  section :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t fall in the trap of micromanagement!</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/11/29/dont-fall-in-the-trap-of-micromanagement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/11/29/dont-fall-in-the-trap-of-micromanagement.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Every employee needs guidance and direction in order to translate the company’s vision and strategy in his•her day to day job. That’s where managers play a key role – and good ones can really make a difference in an organization. Issues arise when someone shifts from managing to micromanaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-micromanagement&quot;&gt;What is micromanagement?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromanagement occurs when, instead of giving general instructions and supervising only the approach and the overall objective, the manager follows and evaluates every step of the project, failing to delegate to his•her subordinates or employees the responsibility they should bear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromanagers tend to obsess on every little detail of everything instead of looking at the big picture. They are overly critical and controlling and push aside the qualification and experience of others. They are petty dictators and constantly interfere with their employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The corporate world is littered with such micromanagers. According to American consultant Harry Chambers, author of the book &lt;em&gt;My Way or the High­way : The Micro­mana­gement Survival Guide&lt;/em&gt;, nearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getabstract.com/en/summary/leadership-and-management/my-way-or-the-highway/4658/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;8 out of 10 employees report that they work for micromanagers or have in the past&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-managers-micromanage&quot;&gt;Why do managers micromanage?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managers who tend to micromanage do so for different reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An attention to detail taken to the extreme;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Their incompetence;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Their insecurity and lack of self-esteem, or even some kind of malignant narcissism or the expression of an obsessive-compulsive disorder;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;External pressure (organizational culture, pressure on delay and performance, instability of the job, etc.);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A managerial tactic in order to make an unwanted employee leave. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This behavior is found more specifically with intermediary managers, who are being stranded between the high expectations of their boss and the pressure of their team members and tend to lose control of the situation little by little and take refuge in an oppressive behavior for others and themselves. In fact, according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_principle&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peter principle&lt;/a&gt;, the more you progress within your company, the more you’ll face such managers who’ve reached their “level of incompetence”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-damaging-effects-of-micromanagement&quot;&gt;The damaging effects of micromanagement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/quote-steve-jobs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effects of micromanagement are immediate for the company:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-overall-productivity-decreases&quot;&gt;The overall productivity decreases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust is the foundation of any successful relationship, whether professionally or personally. When employees feel they can’t trust their boss, they feel unsafe and spend more energy on survival than performing at their job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-innovation-is-reduced&quot;&gt;The innovation is reduced&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they distrust their manager, employees can’t share new idea openly by fear of being shut down. As a consequence, the team/company tends to be stuck in their way of doing things, blocking any form of innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;employees-are-infantilized-and-less-autonomous&quot;&gt;Employees are infantilized and less autonomous&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So long proactivity and independence. Micromanaged employees will increasingly lose their autonomy, asking for more and more from the micromanager, caught at his•her own game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;employees-are-under-stress-and-have-a-lower-morale&quot;&gt;Employees are under stress and have a lower morale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being micromanaged is highly demotivating for employees, all the more for the best ones. This toxic environment generates stress and a lower self-esteem, damaging the atmosphere of the whole company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;employees-have-a-low-scope-of-learning&quot;&gt;Employees have a low scope of learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By being constantly told what they should or shouldn’t do, employees can’t learn by themselves. As a result, their development is hindered, which is prejudicial for their evolution and the future needs of the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-turnover-rises&quot;&gt;The turnover rises&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Micromanagement tends to kill the feeling of loyalty of the employees. Out of demotivation, the best people will look for what they need elsewhere at some point: a healthy workplace where they can make good use of their talents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-go-from-micromanagement-to-trust-and-empowerment&quot;&gt;How to go from micromanagement to trust and empowerment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few “recipes” to cure yourself of your tendency to micromanage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn to trust, while being attuned to your collaborators with &lt;a href=&quot;https://teammood.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;regular feedback&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop focusing on the minor errors of your collaborators in order to appreciate the whole picture;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn to delegate tasks and empower your team members;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instead of drowning your team with details, focus on the end result;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Favor initiatives and autonomy;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t avoid the confrontation of points of view, but make your collaborators participate in the debate and use open questions;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accept the lack of control and tolerate failure – you can start with letting go of less strategical topics;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inject flexibility in the organization (remote working, flexible working hours, …) and set a global objective;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accept to waste time in the beginning in order to save some later;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think collectively;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Believe in the qualification and experience of the team;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a solid line of communication with the team and foster open and honest discussions;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get help from a mentor or a coach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/micromanagement-make-best-people-quit-brigette-hyacinth/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brigette Hyacinth&lt;/a&gt;, author of &lt;em&gt;The Future of Leadership: Rise of Automation, Robotics and Artificial Intelligence,&lt;/em&gt; said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In this volatile global marketplace, happy and loyal employees are your biggest competitive advantage. If you want performance at scale: Select the right people, provide them with the proper training, tools, and support, and then give them room to get the job done!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>[Interview] Diving into Agile and Scrum, the Personal Experience of a Startup Founder</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/11/14/interview-diving-into-agile-and-scrum-the-personal-experience-of-a-startup-founder.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/11/14/interview-diving-into-agile-and-scrum-the-personal-experience-of-a-startup-founder.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Former startupper, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregoiredepins/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gregoire&lt;/a&gt; started working in digital 6 years ago. Since the closing of his startup Sharette (in 2016), he’s offering his services as a freelance consultant, sharing the experience he gained with small and medium-sized companies, and even big corporations: Open Innovation programs, Scrum/Agile coaching, digital marketing strategy (acquisition funnel, SEO, SEA, …).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;blob:https://app.cloudcannon.com/1b660950-5780-4ac0-999c-1c88978379db&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exploring-agile&quot;&gt;Exploring Agile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered Agile methods and more specifically Scrum when I launched my startup in 2012. Like everyone else, I had heard of it. But like everyone else, I didn’t really get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was initially trying to define the best governance model in order to optimize the functioning of the team, without wasting people’s time or the company’s. The question was: when to gather who and what for? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The developers of the team told me about it, as Scrum is specifically well fitted for digital teams composed mainly of developers, and including a product owner. It was exactly our case. Plus we needed to constantly develop and test new functionalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-with-scrum&quot;&gt;Getting started with Scrum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest, I didn’t know anything about Scrum. I started reading articles and talking about it with the team and other entrepreneurs who were experiencing similar situations. I learned and trained myself on the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started implementing meetings and made them evolve over time. For instance, at the beginning, we had weekly sprints: the sprint planning was taking place on Monday morning and on Friday afternoon we had our sprint demo and retrospective. But I soon realized that one week was too short: too often, developers were saying that they didn’t have time for the Friday retro as they had to finish working on tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we adopted this format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-week sprints (in general)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the morning of the 1st day: 4-hour sprint planning meeting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the afternoon of the last day: 45-minute demo followed by a 45-minute &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/02/07/a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;retrospective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every morning of the sprint: short &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/18/best-practices-to-run-effective-daily-standup-meetings.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;daily meeting&lt;/a&gt; at a set time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These meetings included the developers (the “Team”), the product owner (making the link between the Team and the client), and the Scrum Master (bailer of the methodology, rotating among all the developers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improving-our-scrum-practice&quot;&gt;Improving our Scrum practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we struggled most with was the sprint planning (and we’re not the only ones). We had a hard time dividing up the work into well-defined stories that were achievable during the sprint. Little by little, we started calculating/assessing the complexity of each task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complexity assessment is a very effective Scrum technique in order to better allocate the team’s time and effort. The idea is to break down each high-level User Story (also called an Epic) into smaller tasks, and to evaluate for each task its level of complexity using the Fibonacci suite: 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13… The gap between two levels of complexity grows bigger as the complexity increases, which forces the team to make a real choice. Any task above 8 should be broken down again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 = it’s very easy, I know how to do it and I’ll do it quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 = I don’t think it’s very complex but I have a small doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 = it’s rather easy but I need to do some researches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product owner constantly receives feedback from the client on the new functionalities. He shares them with the team at the beginning of the new sprint. He also adds new ideas in the backlog every day, and order them by priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also got stricter on the last day, even if everything that was planned during the sprint planning isn’t finished. On the set day, we stop everything and we compute the number of complexity points we managed to overcome, called the “Velocity”, in order to plan the next sprint. If the sprint was well planned and team members got exactly the right amount of complexity points to work on, this velocity can be used to plan the next sprint. Otherwise, the product owner can increase or decrease it, based on the team’s feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another trap of Scrum is the daily meeting: not having a fixed time, taking it for an operational meeting instead of only sharing information, and being too long. Over time, we chose a fixed hour in the morning (between 9 and 11 am depending on the team), and everyone was supposed to share his or her progress and difficulties in no more than 1 minute. Operational work was left for after the daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-limits-of-scrum&quot;&gt;The limits of Scrum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it couldn’t be all rosy. Scrum is amazing in some contexts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital projects with a level of uncertainty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With a Team (= developers) of 15 people maximum (if the team is bigger, it should be divided into smaller squads)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The team members should be dedicated to the project (working at least 50% of their time on it)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The overall project must be divided into some blocs (the stories) with regular releases and deployments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even in other areas of the company (marketing, HR, …), as long as the team isn’t in charge of long actions constrained by external dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but impossible in others:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the project cannot be divided into small pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the team cannot get regular user feedbacks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If developers are spread among several projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the project is constrained by external dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/when-is-scrum-appropriate.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scrumreferencecard.com/scrum-reference-card/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://scrumreferencecard.com/scrum-reference-card/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing-other-agile-methodologies-extreme-programming-xp&quot;&gt;Testing other Agile methodologies: extreme programming (XP)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never used eXtreme Programming in my startup, but I experienced it with one of my clients. The principle of XP is to divide the Team into pairs: one developer does the coding, and the other one reviews the code along the way. And the tandems rotate at the beginning of each sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem a waste of time to have only one developer out of two actually coding – many think so. It’s true. But this methodology has a lot of advantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It helps produce a code of higher quality and stronger, thus ultimately it saves money.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It reduces the need for maintenance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It develops the competencies of the whole team, and developers love it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It fosters collaboration and friendliness among team members as they know each other better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, I’ve had the opportunity to work and implement Scrum in several teams and companies. In the end, the most difficult in Scrum or other Agile methods is not to understand them, but to put them in place and to &lt;strong&gt;keep the rigor over time. But when you do so, it becomes an amazing playground!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Emotional Seismograph, a Fun and Effective Retrospective Format</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/10/30/the-emotional-seismograph-a-fun-and-effective-retrospective-format.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/10/30/the-emotional-seismograph-a-fun-and-effective-retrospective-format.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/02/07/a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Retrospectives&lt;/a&gt; are fundamental to Agile teams, and very important to all kinds of organization that wants to adapt over time and continuously improve the way they work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle is simple: every set of time (a sprint or a period you decide), the team gathers to reflect on what happened in the timeframe and to identify actions for improvement going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrospectives can follow thousands of formats: Positive &amp;amp; True, Learning Matrix, Worked Well Do Differently, AHA… (you can get inspiration from &lt;a href=&quot;https://retromat.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Retromat&lt;/a&gt;). But one is our favorite and dear to our heart: the &lt;strong&gt;Emotional Seismograph&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to use the Emotional Seismograph?&lt;/strong&gt; Not all the time, but using it now and then can bring novelty to your retrospectives. It’s usually perceived as funner than the other formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use it?&lt;/strong&gt; During your retrospective, each team member shares his or her mood throughout the sprint/timeframe and explains the reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The first 3 days I was feeling very enthusiastic about the project. Then my kids at home got sick and I didn’t sleep much until the middle of the second week. It got a bit better, and then I chose a task that I struggled with way more than I expected. It got me very frustrated for a couple of days, until Mickael helped me get through it. And the last few days, I was a bit stressed to get everything done until the end of the sprint.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some moods can be the result of personal events, which means that the team cannot do anything about them – but it is still valuable to know. Others depend on the team and project itself, and can be food for thoughts to improve the internal functioning for the next spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting your Emotional Seismograph to the next level:&lt;/strong&gt; By using a tool like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/en/agile-retrospective/&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;, you can track your mood along the sprint and avoid forgetting personal and professional events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://visualhunt.com/author2/0e544c&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Crashmaster007&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://visualhunt.com/re/6694b1&quot;&gt;Visual hunt&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-NC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 (Easy) Ways To Improve The Mood In The Workplace</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/09/26/10-easy-ways-to-improve-the-mood-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/09/26/10-easy-ways-to-improve-the-mood-in-the-workplace.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAEAAAABCAYAAAAfFcSJAAAADUlEQVQYV2NYtWrVfwAG/gL+NbCogwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;cms-image-placeholder&quot; /&gt;Your team’s mood depends on hundreds of criteria – many of whom you can’t control. But some simple gimmicks can lighten the mood and generate a better spirit in the long term, with little investment from your part. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some &lt;strong&gt;simple and concrete ways to improve your team’s mood&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduce-plants-in-the-office&quot;&gt;#1 Introduce plants in the office&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introducing plants in your office can be beneficial on all levels. First, studies show that &lt;a href=&quot;http://ellisonchair.tamu.edu/health-and-well-being-benefits-of-plants/#.VgrduivNMUk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;plants can help people better focus and concentrate on their work&lt;/a&gt;, leading to higher overall productivity. Moreover, by producing oxygen all day long, they help freshen the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/office-1696739-640.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plants also serve as a reminder of the natural world outside, and create a calmer, more welcoming environment. They’re certainly easier on the eyes than a sterile white wall or boring office furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;offer-healthy-snacks&quot;&gt;#2 Offer healthy snacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many offices offer coffee or sweet snacks to their employees. Why not differentiate yourself by offering some healthy snacks as well? Fruits, vegetables, and nuts are great examples and boost your employees’ energy throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/apples-bananas-basket-235294.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By taking care of your employees and health, you show them that you care about them. You’ll improve both their mood and productivity, and foster loyalty at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-up-some-fun-goals-or-challenges-for-your-team&quot;&gt;#3 Set up some fun goals or challenges for your team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.themuse.com/career/what-i-learned-about-management-from-a-road-trip/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Setting team goals&lt;/a&gt; is the backbone of every management strategy, but projects goals and yearly performance metrics can be hard to relate to on a daily basis. Involve your team to define immediate goals and challenges, and not only work-related. They can be goofy things like reaching a team bagel consumption goal or competing to find the weirdest daily news story. This will set up a work environment where fun is appreciated as much as hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;run-retrospectives&quot;&gt;#4 Run retrospectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the time to reflect on your past Sprint / month / the set of time you’d like is an amazing way to reflect on past events, to praise your employees’ work, and to identify issues you need to resolve. Having this time and space to express themselves will encourage your employees to invest in improving the processes and internal functioning of the team. By running &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/02/07/a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;retrospectives&lt;/a&gt;, your team will grow stronger and happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bring-pastries-or-croissants-at-weeklymonthly-team-meetings&quot;&gt;#5 Bring pastries or croissants at weekly/monthly team meetings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetings. We all need them but we all fear them. If &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/18/best-practices-to-run-effective-daily-standup-meetings.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;daily meetings&lt;/a&gt; should stay short, why not lighting up the mood for longer ones (weekly meetings, monthly retrospectives…) by bringing some nice pastries or croissants? You don’t have to do it yourself all the time, the bringer can rotate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, with this ritual, you’ll make sure everyone arrives on time if they don’t want to see their croissant taken from their hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;encourage-fitness-or-sports-activities&quot;&gt;#6 Encourage fitness or sports activities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sport is good for your health, your concentration… and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.muhealth.org/conditions-treatments/pediatrics/adolescent-medicine/benefits-of-sports&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;your spirit&lt;/a&gt;. Encouraging your employees to practice a sport (if they want to) will help them be at ease with themselves. If you have some spare space in your office, you can schedule fitness or yoga classes during the lunch break or install a gym. Another (smaller) alternative is to install a bathroom for runners to take a shower before going back to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If indoor is out of the question, you can also participate in a yearly gym membership, or set aside an hour each week from work for your employees to participate in yoga, wall climbing, volleyball, or any sport they may like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, you can promote team sports as team building activities all along the year, or during a company outing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;celebrate-personal-events&quot;&gt;#7 Celebrate personal events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By investing in your employees’ personal lives, you can show them that they matter for the company. Not everyone likes to share openly their personal life and events (birthday, wedding, birth of a child…), but if you pay attention to your teammates, you can find a way to demonstrate your true interest: bringing a birthday cake, have flowers or a gift sent over their home, …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;show-some-gratitudenbsp&quot;&gt;#8 Show some gratitude &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By managing your team or a project, you can easily forget that they are human beings. Recognizing their effort and good work can have a huge impact on their morale. A simple way to demonstrate gratitude among your teammates is to implement &lt;a href=&quot;https://management30.com/product/kudo-cards/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kudo cards&lt;/a&gt;: small tokens of appreciation that managers and teammates can give each other. “Congratulations”, “Thank you”, “You rock”, “Great job”, “Well done”, the options are endless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/kudo-cards-300x197.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudo cards are very efficient to increase recognition of valued work, which encourages intrinsic motivation within an organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;offer-time-away-from-the-office-to-do-some-good&quot;&gt;#9 Offer time away from the office to do some good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking part in a charity or a volunteering action encourages both the company and employees to give back to the community. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/02/managers-do-you-know-how-to-work-with-millennials.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Investing in causes they care about is especially important for millennial workers&lt;/a&gt; according to a Deloitte study. By dedicating some time during the year to volunteer, you can show your employees that they are aligned with the company’s values, and give them a feeling of empowerment and influence over world and local issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not ask your team for suggested charities and events, and make it a group decision? Not only will this help with to encourage team spirit but it also shows how the company seeks out ideas for their employees in decision making and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;grant-time-off-to-employees-to-pursue-projects-they-are-passionate-about&quot;&gt;#10 Grant time off to employees to pursue projects they are passionate about&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking on some personal projects can provide an energizing break from regular responsibilities, and can be a source of innovation for your company. At Google for instance, employees are given a day every week to pursue a personal project, no questions asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you grant some free time to your employees to work on personal projects, some may lead to new ideas for the company, most of them will probably not. But most of all, you are giving them a breath of fresh air they will be thankful for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your turn now. &lt;strong&gt;Have you implemented any other technique to improve your team’s mood?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Reduce Stress at Work: 12 Strategies to Handle Stressful Careers</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/08/28/how-to-reduce-stress-at-work-12-strategies-to-handle-stressful-careers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/08/28/how-to-reduce-stress-at-work-12-strategies-to-handle-stressful-careers.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overwhelmed. Nervous. Exhausted. Agitated. Pained. All at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, if you’re like, well, pretty much every worker ever, you know what we’re talking about: stress. No matter your job, work stress is like the zero on a roulette wheel: it’s coming around eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, as a species we’ve developed a host of strategies — large and small — for managing stress. We’re going to share 12 with you. Why 12? Because it’s the least stressful number, of course!*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Note: scientific backing for this may be minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-biggies-sleep-eat-right-exercise&quot;&gt;1. The Biggies: Sleep, Eat right, Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you’ve heard these all before. Too bad. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/stress/2013/sleep.aspx&quot;&gt;Scientific study after scientific study&lt;/a&gt; has validated the effectiveness of all these things for relieving stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleeping, eating right, and exercising are all great for your physical health, but more importantly, they also do wonders for psychological health. All three help boost endorphins, regulate dopamine, and simply keep you happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn’t mean you can’t cheat. (Because sometimes the best stress relief is binge-watching Game of Thrones with a pint of chocolate chip cookie dough ice cream.) But if you want to &lt;a href=&quot;https://virtualspeech.com/blog/managing-anxiety-stress-workplace&quot;&gt;manage the stress&lt;/a&gt; you already have while simultaneously helping bullet-proof yourself from stress in the future, you owe it to yourself to start thinking about all these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;establish-boundaries&quot;&gt;2. Establish Boundaries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often the source of work stress is the feeling that work can never end. That feeling’s certainly grown as electronic communication ensures you can always be found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or does it? Sometimes the best stress-prevention technique is to work on saying no. No emails after 9pm. No work on the weekends. No letting managers add more work to your already-too-full plate. You don’t have to choose all of these, but you should choose the one or two that matter to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reduce-interruptions&quot;&gt;3. Reduce Interruptions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies prove it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/05/05/opinion/sunday/a-focus-on-distraction.html&quot;&gt;interruptions&lt;/a&gt; make us more agitated. That’s why one good strategy is to keep interruptions to a minimum. Turn off your internet connection for a while. Or at least close your email reader and chat windows. Put a “do not disturb” sign on your door or cubicle. Wear big headphones so that people know not to bother you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll get more done and won’t feel pulled in a million directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;write-things-down&quot;&gt;4. Write Things Down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too much going on in your head? Use an old technology to help: pencil and paper. When you’re stressed out because you have too much to keep track of, take a sheet of paper and write down everything you have to do. (Or use an app like RTM, or Trello.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not having to worry about remembering what you have to do frees up a surprising amount of emotional energy to actually do those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prioritize-to-immediately-reduce-work-stress&quot;&gt;5. Prioritize to Immediately Reduce Work Stress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it feels like you’ll just never get everything done, sometimes you just need to realize that you don’t have to. Make a list of all the tasks on your plate, then decide what really has to get done, and what you’d just like to have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean that what you’d like to get done isn’t important. But you can worry about that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;clean-up-your-desk-or-workspace&quot;&gt;6. Clean up Your Desk or Workspace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, studies show that a cluttered desk helps raise work stress levels. Often when everything else feels unruly, taking 30 minutes to organize your workspace can bring a relieving feeling of calm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/oCGjUWkj8vz9u&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;271&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: this same strategy applies to your apartment, your house, your car, your briefcase, or any other place you keep your stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;show-up-early&quot;&gt;7. Show up Early&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get stressed because you’re always running behind schedule, what can do the trick is coming to work 10 minutes early every day. Get some coffee, put your stuff away, and plan out your day. By the time “worktime” hits, you’re already rolling!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;listen-to-music&quot;&gt;8. Listen to Music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William Congreve wrote that “Musick has Charms to sooth a savage Breast.” He’s right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/l0MYEpCzZTQqdQSju&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need a little de-stressing at work, throw on the headphones and dial up whatever tunes make you happy. Beyonce? Bach? 2-Pac? Doesn’t really matter — if you’re digging it, you’re feeling better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule-in-breaks&quot;&gt;9. Schedule in Breaks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting to feel like the only way to manage a stressful workload is to power through it, non-stop. Turns out that’s actually counter-productive. It’s a fact: breaks let you get more done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re worried about all the work you have to do, set breaks for yourself. Work hard for 25 minutes, then walk around for 10. Work hard for another 25 minutes, then read something stupid online. Give yourself time to recharge; it’ll keep you from burning yourself out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when it is time to take a vacation, be sure to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clicktime.com/time-off-management&quot;&gt;schedule time off&lt;/a&gt; and enjoy some much-needed R&amp;amp;R.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eliminate-unnecessary-meetings&quot;&gt;10. Eliminate Unnecessary Meetings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is falls more into “larger strategies” than “things to do right now.” That said, at plenty of workplaces, meetings pile on until there’s no time to simply sit down and work. That’s stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter where you are on the totem pole, you’ll be helping everyone else on your team if you advocate for dropping unnecessary meetings. There’ll be fewer things to worry about, and you’ll free up more time for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reward-yourself-for-working&quot;&gt;11. Reward Yourself for Working&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the best cure for stress is to simply be nice to yourself. And what better reason is there to be nice to yourself than for having done some good work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with breaks (see #9 above), small rewards can be a great way to keep yourself productive, while helping you tally the amount of work you’ve actually gotten done. So work hard for a while, then reward yourself by writing to a friend. Or having a small treat. Or leaving the office for 10 minutes. By holding those rewards back until you’ve earned them, you’ll be more motivated to work. But by giving them to yourself, you’ll tell yourself you deserve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-thankful&quot;&gt;12. Be Thankful&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silly as it might sound, cultivating a thankful attitude can reduce both general and work stress, and make you happier. As a general life practice, working to be more thankful is one of the best ways to keep you stress-free (or at least stress-reduced).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/26gsjCZpPolPr3sBy&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of ways to do this. Keep a gratitude journal. Force yourself to say “thank you” to three people a day. Spend 5 minutes every night going over what you’re thankful for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whichever of these you choose, keep doing it. In a short period of time, you’ll notice how much better you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the author&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;This is a guest post by the folks at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clicktime.com/&quot;&gt;ClickTime&lt;/a&gt;. They know a lot about the stress stuffs as they work on time management.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 13:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Evaluating Your Team’s Health With the Niko-Niko Calendar</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/07/24/evaluating-your-teams-health-with-the-niko-niko-calendar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/07/24/evaluating-your-teams-health-with-the-niko-niko-calendar.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Would you go out of your house with a rain coat if it wasn’t for the weather forecast to warn you of the rain coming up? How about the stock market: would you invest in shares without checking their values and trend? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In team management, you can have all sorts of KPIs to measure and display how well your team is doing: productivity, lead time, bugs, … Tracking those metrics helps the team to identify problems early and improve. The only one that is missing is the actual mood and motivation of your team members. And I don’t need to tell you &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html&quot;&gt;how important it is for the good of the project&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the reason why, a few years ago (in 2006 more precisely), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.jp/nikonikocalendar/index_en.html&quot;&gt;Akinori SAKATA&lt;/a&gt; invented the &lt;strong&gt;Niko Niko calendar&lt;/strong&gt;, a.k.a. the smiley calendar or the happiness index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/happy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Happy worker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-niko-niko-calendar&quot;&gt;What is the Niko-niko calendar?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko calendar is the application of a very important principle in Agile project management defined by american engineer and Agile expert Tom Gilb:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Anything you need to quantify can be measured in some way that is superior to not measuring it at all.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The measure doesn’t have to be perfect nor precise. The objective is to quantify something that wasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/nikoniko-calendar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Niko-Niko calendar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how does the Niko-niko calendar work? It’s a simple calendar with everybody’s name on it. At the end of the day, each team member is invited to share their mood of the day, sticking smilies happy 😄, straight 😬 or frowning 🙁 or color stickers on it. That’s actually where its name comes from: Niko means smile in Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko doesn’t provide an exact measure of the team’s mood, but it helps quantifying the well-being, morale and motivation – three factors that are usually difficult to measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team’s spirit is even more important for an Agile team as the success of the project relies on it. It’s the reason why the Niko-niko calendar was first invented for Agile teams. It provides a general view of how well the team is doing, and not just at individual level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-use-the-niko-niko-method&quot;&gt;How to use the Niko-niko method?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko must follow some principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone’s mood should be visible to the others&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It should never be hold against someone or be considered as an individual objective&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The moods should be observed during the next day’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/18/best-practices-to-run-effective-daily-standup-meetings.html&quot;&gt;daily meeting&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The manager / team leader / scrum master should try to understand and treat “abnormality”, good or bad: a common bad day shared by the whole team, a person that is constantly happy while the rest of the team is unhappy and vice-versa, a general deterioration of the team’s mood, a shared “happy” mood even if the project isn’t good wel…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/sad.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Sad worker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In concrete terms, to use the Niko-niko method, you can build &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/diy/2013/05/07/build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar.html&quot;&gt;your own Niko-niko calendar&lt;/a&gt; with a daily calendar and a stack of color stickers. Or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/en/Niko-Niko/&quot;&gt;choose to use an online tool&lt;/a&gt; if your team is working remotely, or simply if you want to be able to analyze trends. An online tool can also help you gather comments more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-leverage-the-niko-niko-calendar&quot;&gt;How to leverage the Niko-niko calendar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t let your Niko-niko hang there for nothing! Quantifying your team’s mood is only the first step, you need to be able to act on it, where your team is in a good or bad mood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/05/16/your-team-is-in-a-bad-mood-heres-what-you-need-to-do.html&quot;&gt;Reacting to one of several teammates’ bad mood&lt;/a&gt; can seem pretty obvious: you don’t want a bad situation to degenerate, and you need your team to be at its best in order to deliver results. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/06/12/how-to-leverage-your-teams-good-mood.html&quot;&gt;understanding and leveraging your team’s good mood&lt;/a&gt; is also very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data from a Niko-niko calendar is a huge opportunity for reflection. You can get instant feedback from changes that are altering the work environment. It can also be included in a reporting for top management (leaving it anonymous).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Are you convinced? Start implementing a Niko-niko calendar in your team, either by &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/diy/2013/05/07/build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar.html&quot;&gt;building it yourself&lt;/a&gt;, of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/en/Niko-Niko/&quot;&gt;using an online one such as TeamMood&lt;/a&gt; and tell us what you think.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 07:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Cultivate a Workplace Culture of Gratitude</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/07/04/how-to-cultivate-a-workplace-culture-of-gratitude.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/07/04/how-to-cultivate-a-workplace-culture-of-gratitude.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Around &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/global/Documents/About-Deloitte/gx-core-beliefs-and-culture.pdf&quot;&gt;88% of employees and 94% of executives&lt;/a&gt; say that they believe company culture is crucial to success. If you want to create a powerful environment for your business, then you need to be willing to prize and prioritize the right ideas for your employees. For instance, one value worth cultivating is “gratitude”. Employees who are thankful for where they are and what they accomplish will constantly go above and beyond to serve their employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is, how do you bring a culture of gratitude into your workplace? The following steps could help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-by-setting-an-example&quot;&gt;1. Start by Setting an Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you want to implement a change in your company culture, the first thing you need to do is think about how you can set the right example. Remember, as the owner or manager of your business, you’re not just someone who cuts pay-checks and tells people what to do every day. You’re the leader that your employees turn to when they’re looking for advice and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/thanks.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Showing gratitude&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people see you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/karlsun/2017/12/18/how-to-create-a-culture-of-gratitude-in-the-workplace/&quot;&gt;practicing gratitude every day&lt;/a&gt;, they’ll start to embrace the concept as a natural part of your workplace culture. So, how do you bring gratitude into your life? That’s simple. All you need to do is start showing your appreciation for things - both little and big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone accomplishes a task in your organization, show them how much you appreciate it by giving them a pat on the back. When you meet your goals or targets, share that with your team and show them how every success adds up in the long term. And more importantly, demonstrate &lt;strong&gt;the right values and behaviors&lt;/strong&gt;, because that’s what matters the most in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;recognize-your-employees-in-the-way-they-prefer&quot;&gt;2. Recognize Your Employees in the Way They Prefer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognition is one of the most powerful things changing modern workforces. In fact, according to some studies, approximately &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.workstars.com/recognition-and-engagement-blog/2017/08/18/10-knockout-employee-recognition-statistics-for-hr-infographic/&quot;&gt;69% of employees&lt;/a&gt; say that they would work harder and take on more responsibilities if they felt their efforts were appreciated. If you want to make sure that you’re building a culture of gratitude for your organization, start by thanking your employees for their hard work in a manner they can really resonate with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some small achievements, a simple “thank you” can be enough to make your staff feel better about their career. For bigger accomplishments, you might look for more significant ways to show your recognition. For instance, you could throw an office party celebrating a huge client win or share a company newsletter that highlights your top performers. Some organization still think that the “employee of the month” strategy works well as a way of keeping their hires happy too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;give-your-people-reasons-to-be-thankful&quot;&gt;3. Give Your People Reasons to be Thankful&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world where countless companies are beginning to explore ideas like remote working to help their employees tackle stress and workplace gyms for wellbeing, it pays to go above and beyond for your staff. If you want your employees to feel excited by the fact that they’re part of your team, and you’re hoping that your reputation as an excellent employer will spread to lure new talent to your company, then look for creative ways to make your staff smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The little extras and benefits you put into place to delight your team will depend on what they appreciate most. For instance, academic minds might like it if you sign them up for trips to regular conferences and training sessions. Plenty of employees like having an opportunity to expand and improve their skills. Providing this education not only makes your hires happy, but also gives you access to new talents too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, giving your employees a reason to be thankful could be as simple as signing them up for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.javapresse.com/pages/subscriptions-gifts&quot;&gt;monthly coffee subscription&lt;/a&gt;, so that they can enjoy fresh java every day. This not only stops people from complaining about the stale drinks you previously had in your office kitchen, it also gives your team the antioxidants and great flavor they need to boost their mood and their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;look-for-ways-to-give-back&quot;&gt;4. Look for Ways to Give Back&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embracing a true culture of gratitude means more than giving something back to your employees. It could also mean that you look for ways to support your community and local causes that need your help. Signing up for a partnership with a charity that your team cares about and giving them paid leave to go and offer their services to that organization is a great way to share the idea of gratitude far and wide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborating with charities gives your employees an opportunity to express their gratitude for the privileges they enjoy as part of your company, and essentially share the wealth. As well as allowing staff to take part in formal programs, you could also ask employees to come up with and suggest their own initiatives. You’d be surprised how much a caring nature matters to today’s hires. Modern employees - particularly those in the millennial demographic, like to feel as though they’re having an impact on the world around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing your team that you’re willing to give something back both improves your culture of gratitude and may help you to attract new candidates to your company too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-time-to-reflect&quot;&gt;5. Take Time to Reflect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, sometimes the best way to nurture a culture of gratitude in your company is to simply slow down. When you stop rushing around after deadlines and take the time to stop and smell the coffee every now and again, it’s easier to reflect on where you are, and where you came from. Although running a business can be hard work, when you begin to reflect, you’ll realize just how lucky you’ve been so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in the toughest of times, most of us have something to be grateful for. Whether it’s a family back home that supports you or a great USP in your business, make sure that you appreciate what you have. Try to encourage moments of reflection for your team, so that they never lose sight of the positive things in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;give-a-purpose&quot;&gt;6. Give a Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team should have clear, achievable milestones with a good plan, eg prioritized things to do. When the deliverables are shipped, make sure that the team gets the feedback about them, about how they really impacted the customers, so that the individuals feel they made a difference in something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the author&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Raj Jana is the CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.javapresse.com/pages/subscriptions-gifts&quot;&gt;JavaPresse&lt;/a&gt; and a strong advocate of the power of company culture. He enjoys sharing his advice on how to build a successful company and often uses his experiences to help him write insightful articles for blogs across the internet. Company culture has quickly become one of the most important components of a successful business. After all, your people can either make or break your company. If they’re happy and satisfied with their jobs, then they’re sure to be more productive and focused in their roles. On the other hand, if they’re constantly looking forward to the moment that they can clock out and go home, then your organization will struggle to thrive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kuddos to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tobias-flanders-5a031656/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tobias Flanders&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/emily-sattout-4a03b77b/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Emily Sattout&lt;/a&gt; for the comments and edits of the article&lt;/em&gt; 🙌&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 08:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Leverage Your Team’s Good Mood</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/06/12/how-to-leverage-your-teams-good-mood.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/06/12/how-to-leverage-your-teams-good-mood.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Is happiness in the air? Are your teammates smiling and joking around? Is your team productivity skyrocketing? Congratulations, your team is in a good mood! And the results are there: your team delivers in no time, the job is well-done, they are more creative and thorough… The dream comes true :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what’s next? If you rest on your laurels and hope for the situation to go on forever, you will most certainly be disappointed. Just like &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/05/16/your-team-is-in-a-bad-mood-heres-what-you-need-to-do.html&quot;&gt;when your team is experiencing a bad mood&lt;/a&gt;, you must understand the causes for this happy mood in order to keep it going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-the-situation-permanent-or-temporary&quot;&gt;Is the situation permanent or temporary?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you recently noticed a sudden change of mood or is the situation more or less stable? And if it’s stable, has is always been like that or has the situation evolve over the months/years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half a century ago, American researcher and professor of educational psychology Bruce Wayne Tuckman developed a theory of group dynamics, published in his article &lt;a href=&quot;http://psycnet.apa.org/record/1965-12187-001&quot;&gt;Developmental sequence in small groups&lt;/a&gt;. According to the Tuckman’s theory of group development, every group grows through 4 phases: Forming, Storming, Norming, Performing and Adjourning. These phases are necessary and inevitable in order for the team to grow, face up to challenges, tackle problems, find solutions, plan work, and deliver results. They are usually followed by a fifth phase named “Adjourning”, that involves completing the task and breaking up the team, paving the way for a new exciting project to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/tuckman_s_stages_of_development.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tuckman&#39;s Stages of Development&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Source: http://margarethillary.com/team-work/&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering your happy team, are they currently in a Forming stage? Norming? Performing? Understanding the group dynamic can help you better anticipate the changes and help your teammates be at their utmost performance. Indeed, in each stage, you can use different strategies in order to facilitate the development of high performing teams:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forming: picking the team, discuss the goals, make sure the team develops a shared mental model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forming: act as a resource person to the team, develop mutual trust and calm the work environment by resolving conflicts and tensions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Norming &amp;amp; Performing: get feedback from your teammates, allow for the transfer of leadership, set aside time for planning and engaging the team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outperforming &amp;amp; Adjourning: expand initiatives and integrate new members, allow for flexibility in team roles, create future leadership opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-the-root-or-simple-causes&quot;&gt;What are the (root or simple) causes?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If root causes can be explained by Tuckman’s stages, a good mood can simply be the consequence of a team building activity that was particularly appreciated, a habit to bring in croissants at the end of each sprint, a new wellness program…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a manager, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html&quot;&gt;boost wellbeing and happiness at work&lt;/a&gt; with theses simple acts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a culture of trust and transparency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/07/04/how-to-cultivate-a-workplace-culture-of-gratitude.html&quot;&gt;Show gratitude and value positive intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Foster empowerment and accountability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Favor breaks and downtime&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Launch a project that people care about / are proud of&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Favor friendship and informal times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And more than anything else, don’t forget to take the time to celebrate successes or good news with your team. These moments of commemoration and gratitude are essential to keep your team’s motivation up and pave the way to new challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you cannot manage everything, some external sources can cause a happy or bad mood, beyond your control. The best thing you can do? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/&quot;&gt;Ask your team members&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your team is in a bad mood? Here’s what you need to do.</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/05/16/your-team-is-in-a-bad-mood-heres-what-you-need-to-do.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/05/16/your-team-is-in-a-bad-mood-heres-what-you-need-to-do.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Either you are sensing there is an issue in your team or you are using a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/&quot;&gt;tool&lt;/a&gt; that tells you so, you can’t afford to ignore it. Indeed, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html&quot;&gt;a bad mood will affect your team productivity&lt;/a&gt;: unhappy people are proven to be &lt;strong&gt;10% less productive&lt;/strong&gt; than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if a bad situation arises, here is what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-to-the-roots-of-the-problem&quot;&gt;1 - Get to the roots of the problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel some tension among team members, unspoken issues or a general growing discontent, you need to understand where it’s coming from. Small quarrels or disagreements are usually fueled by a deeper issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/why.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Chicken and pigs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a stressful deadline coming up? Were there a change in the strategic orientation of the product? Is the company to be going through a bad patch? A specific individual driving everyone’s morale down?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/04/11/8-warnings-that-a-crisis-is-looming-among-your-teammates.html&quot;&gt;paying attention to the signs&lt;/a&gt;, big or small, or use a tool to anonymously question your team members such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discuss-the-situation&quot;&gt;2 - Discuss the situation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know (or think to know) the situation and its causes, you must discuss it with your team members, individually or as a team according to the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the bad mood is a general state shared by the whole or part of your team, you can address the issue quickly during a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/18/best-practices-to-run-effective-daily-standup-meetings.html&quot;&gt;Daily standup meeting&lt;/a&gt; or come back to it during a &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/02/07/a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives.html&quot;&gt;Retrospective&lt;/a&gt; (but beware not to let the situation settle in and worsen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it’s more an individual state, let everyone know that you are open and willing to discuss whatever problem they may have. And encourage your team to share their issue in an anonymous comment if they don’t want to discuss it openly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-a-solution-together&quot;&gt;3 - Find a solution together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they say, “Two heads are better than one.” If you try to find a solution on your own, it’s likely that it will fail: your team members may not subscribe to it, or you’ll just miss the point and the responsibility will fall on your shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have different options here: you can choose to discuss the solution in a team meeting, to set up an anonymous idea box or an open board, to have one-on-one formal discussions or a group informal chat during a team afterwork…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arouse-friendliness&quot;&gt;4 - Arouse friendliness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies show that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.snacknation.com/blog/employee-happiness/&quot;&gt;close work friendships&lt;/a&gt; boost employee satisfaction by 50%&lt;/strong&gt; and that people with a &lt;strong&gt;best friend at work are 7 times more likely to engage fully in their work&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/friends-tv-show.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chicken and pigs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a manager, if you want your team to work hard and get results, you need to create the perfect environment. Of course, you can’t force your team members to become friends. But you can create the conditions for people to bond: team afterwork at the end of the sprint, lunch break together once in a while, team building activities…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lead-by-example&quot;&gt;5 - Lead by example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you be in the middle of the storm or simply handle a temporary decrease in employee moral, don’t forget that your attitude as a manager will greatly impact your team members. Set the example by having a positive and open speech, sharing information transparently, being attentive and openly share your own problems. Don’t forget also to show gratitude to your employees and to praise their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply by acknowledging their issues and recognizing their effort and/or results, you can turn the situation around and motivate your team members again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my next article, I will share my advice on how to react to a good mood, instead of resting on one’s laurels. &lt;!-- Subscribe to our newsletter to receive our articles directly in your inbox!--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/&quot;&gt;Start Using TeamMood To Monitor The Mood Of Your Team&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 09:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Practices To Run Effective Daily Standup Meetings</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/18/best-practices-to-run-effective-daily-standup-meetings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/18/best-practices-to-run-effective-daily-standup-meetings.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Daily Meeting (or Daily Scrum) is one of the key elements of Scrum and some other agile methods. It is set to happen every day of a Sprint (= a set period of time during which specific work has to be completed) in order to foster &lt;strong&gt;communication and collaboration between the whole team&lt;/strong&gt;. In order to be effective, a Daily standup Meeting should follow these 8 rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rules-to-run-effective-daily-standup-meetings&quot;&gt;8 rules to run effective Daily Standup Meetings:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;every-day-same-time-same-place&quot;&gt;1 - Every day, same time, same place&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem obvious, but the very first rule to &lt;strong&gt;Daily Meetings is that it should happen every day of a Sprint&lt;/strong&gt;, ideally at the beginning of a working day. Every team member must attend, as it helps to organize the work of the day and to make sure the team as a whole is working towards the completion of the Sprint objectives. It can also prevent two team members from working on the same task without knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stand-up-meeting-aka-daily-scrum&quot;&gt;2 - Stand up meeting AKA “Daily Scrum”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the &lt;strong&gt;core principles of the Daily Scrum is that it should happen standing up&lt;/strong&gt;. It may seem a gimmick but it actually reduces rambling and helps team members staying focused. Being seated, it is very easy to take your laptop or smartphone out and start disengaging from the meeting. Moreover, standing up encourages everyone to keep the meeting short (ideally no more than 15 minutes) and focus on what’s important, keeping the discussions for after the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An easy solution is to hold the meeting in a room without chairs or to put all the chairs on one side of the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some exceptions here, some teams may comfortably sit down if they are using an online Scrum board; in that case, they share the screen, and everyone focuses on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;question-agenda&quot;&gt;3 - 3-question agenda&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Daily Scrum, everyone is supposed to answer those three questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What did you accomplish since the last Daily Meeting?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are you working on until the next Daily Meeting?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is getting in your way or keeping you from doing your job?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Daily Meeting should not be considered as a status report to overlook teammates’ work or micromanage the team. It should really be about fostering discussion and collaboration among team members to make sure everything is going smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2017/12/06/best-practices-from-our-users.html&quot;&gt;The best way to do it is to use a Scrum Board&lt;/a&gt; (physical or online) and post-its to visualize all the tasks to be completed during the Sprint, all the ongoing ones and the ones that are already done. Each team members can comment the task chosen during the last daily, discuss potential issues and select a new one to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;address-problems-without-solving-them&quot;&gt;4 - Address problems without solving them&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third question of the Daily Standup Meeting is key: it’s the perfect occasion to &lt;strong&gt;share an issue or ask for help&lt;/strong&gt;. But don’t you try resolving it right away. The Daily Standup Meeting shouldn’t be a technical one, talking about solutions and choices. If you want to respect your agenda and give the floor to each teammate in the allotted time, keep the technical discussions for after the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, new ideas should be addressed outside the Daily Meeting, in order to leave some space for discussion (which can’t happen in a 15-minute meeting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-team-decides-what-to-do-next&quot;&gt;5 - The team decides what to do next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said earlier, the Daily Scrum Meeting is not an opportunity for the Scrum Master to micro-manage and impose what to do next. In fact, his or her main task is to ensure that the Daily Meetings are held, that the 3 main questions are answered, and that impediments are identified so that a possible resolution can be set in motion. Once the habit of holding Daily Meeting every day is set and the team understand the value of the meeting, they can hold it on their own, the Scrum Master no longer has to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Daily Meeting, each team member can select a task he or she feels like doing, based on their competences, experience and the overall criticality of the tasks. Letting everyone being &lt;strong&gt;his or her own boss&lt;/strong&gt; is the best way to get them &lt;strong&gt;excited and committed to the success of the project&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;giving-the-floor-to-those-who-are-committed&quot;&gt;6 - Giving the floor to those who are committed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the golden rules is: &lt;strong&gt;the Daily Standup Meeting is a meeting for and by those who are committed&lt;/strong&gt;, who are really working on the project. The very aim of the Daily Meeting is to provide a space and time for teammates to discuss. They should be central to the meeting – if other people who are just “involved” (directors, stakeholders…) want to speak, they should wait for the end of the stand-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;http://www.implementingscrum.com/images/060911-scrumtoon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&#39;Don&#39;t be the Chicken during the standup meetings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-scrum-master-makes-the-connection-with-the-outside&quot;&gt;7 - The Scrum Master makes the connection with the outside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Daily Meeting cannot be the sole means of team communication, it can be the opportunity for the Scrum Master to share information if he or she decides to attend. In fact, he or she should act as the information conduit in and out of the team boundary: passing external information to the team, and team information to external stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: “Hey, just to let you know the other team is having a demo of their new feature tomorrow. Maybe you want to go and see.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or “I’ve contacted IT about expediting that new build server… I’ll have more info tomorrow”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or “The marketing team is throwing a happy hour tonight.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;celebrate-success-and-understand-issues&quot;&gt;8 - Celebrate success and understand issues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t make the mistake of taking the Daily Scrum Meeting for a shared to-do list. It’s also the time to &lt;strong&gt;celebrate successes and address issues as a team&lt;/strong&gt;. Using a tool like TeamMood to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/en/features/&quot;&gt;measure your team members’ mood&lt;/a&gt; and feelings can provide you with great insights for your Daily Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Daily Meeting, you can take the time to check in on the history of TeamMood, see if there are small wins or developing trends. Identify small issues you can deal with today like “We ran out of coffee”. Of course, larger issues should be addressed during &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/2018/02/07/a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives.html&quot;&gt;retrospectives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to one of our clients, “During our Daily Meeting, team members could share their thoughts and explain low ratings. TeamMood provided employees with the opportunity to speak up and got a dialogue going on among the team.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another client shares his use of TeamMood: “We take the TeamMood results into the retrospective from time to time, to share comments. However, throughout the sprints, I keep an eye on the team’s mood. Any concerning dips and I will start looking into the cause…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to discover how TeamMood can help you improve your Daily Meetings?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full success story &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/en/success/Success-story-banque-en.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/en/continuous-improvement/&quot;&gt;try TeamMood for free&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andycleff/&quot;&gt;Andy Cleff&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rene-martinussen-a3418216/&quot;&gt;Rene Martinussen&lt;/a&gt; for your comments and edits of the article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Managers, do you know how to work with millennials?</title>
        <link>https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/02/managers-do-you-know-how-to-work-with-millennials.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.teammood.com/2018/04/02/managers-do-you-know-how-to-work-with-millennials.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The key motivation factors in the workplace have shifted along generations, from job security to promotions and career evolution. But more recently, even high paychecks and bonuses don’t seem to matter that much for the new generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;managing-millennials-a-new-challenge&quot;&gt;Managing millennials: a new challenge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, for this new generation, work cannot just be a trivial, down-to-earth activity to make a living. Millennials tend to treat work as an experience, competing with other activities and hobbies. It has to be exciting, fulfilling, rewarding. What’s the point of waking up if it’s just to earn a salary?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, historical incentives don’t work anymore: bonus, promotion, and profit-sharing are unable to motivate employees on their own. Indeed, millennials don’t share their elders’ unbreakable loyalty to their company and can switch easily to a more attractive one – or just leave their job to travel around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/working_with_millenials.png&quot; alt=&quot;Working With Millenials&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same time, attracting and retaining the best talents is of strategic importance for companies. As the environment becomes increasingly competitive, key resources are companies’ most valuable asset. And the process of recruiting and training new employees on a specific job can be very costly. So, here are the 4 main drivers to attract, motivate and retain millennial workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;drivers-that-work-for-the-millennial-worker&quot;&gt;Drivers that work for the millennial worker&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some say that millennials are not interested in working, are lazy and disobedient. That’s wrong, studies prove that they are, as much as their elders, committed to their work. But they are also sensitive to different incentives. And if companies want to attract and retain the best talents, managers need to adapt to these changes and better understand their drivers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;empowerment-and-ownership&quot;&gt;Empowerment and ownership&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that millennial workers don’t accept hierarchy – on the contrary, they strive for a mentor that would make them learn and grow. But they do want to feel empowered, to own their project and be responsible, for better or for worse. Feeling like the simple executant of a task that was decided outside of them drive millennials crazy – you can be sure that they’ll quickly lose their motivation, hence their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is your company organized? Are all decisions taken by the top managers of each branch or do you leave some responsibility to project owners?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flexibility&quot;&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the worst for a millennial at work? To feel like in a prison at work. In order to be motivated and efficient, they want to feel free to organize their day as they wish. They may have a look at Facebook to take a break during their work day, and then answer an email from work at night, from their couch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials also value work-life balance: they want their company to be understanding and flexible about office hours. Arriving later for the late-sleepers or leaving earlier for those who need or want to shouldn’t be a problem. Likewise, millennials really appreciate the freedom to work remotely, at least once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is your company more focused on effort or results? Have you implemented a remote-work policy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-bigger-goal&quot;&gt;A bigger goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work shouldn’t be “just” about making a living, it has to be meaningful. Millennials want to adhere to their company’s values and goal. They want to earn a good living while doing work that matters. According to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.deloitte.com/global/en/pages/about-deloitte/articles/millennialsurvey.html&quot;&gt;Deloitte study&lt;/a&gt;, millennials feel accountable for many issues worldwide. Opportunities to be involved with “good causes” at the local level provide millennials with a greater feeling of influence – even better if enabled by their employers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you defined company values that go beyond economic profit? Do you take on pro bono missions, actively participate in associations or encourage your employees to do so?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunities-to-learn-and-grow&quot;&gt;Opportunities to learn and grow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital generation is keen on learning and acquiring new competencies. The knowledge acquired during university is no longer sufficient and quickly irrelevant. Wikipedia, MOOCs, online diplomas, videos, serious games… everything works to help the millennials grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managers and human resources would better get up to speed. Having a comprehensive learning and development program makes a difference when it’s time to choose the company to work for – and to stick with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you updated your learning and development programs to better fit the company’s needs? Do you take into account employees’ wishes? How much of your payroll do you spend on learning and development?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;new-forms-of-work-in-the-digital-economy&quot;&gt;New forms of work in the digital economy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our digital world, not only the motivation drivers have changed, the work itself is evolving. More and more people choose to work remotely, or even go freelance. And the impact on managers is enormous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, freelance workers already make up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketwired.com/press-release/new-study-finds-freelance-economy-grew-55-million-americans-this-year-35-total-us-workforce-2164446.htm&quot;&gt;35% of the US&lt;/a&gt; workforce and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.staffingindustry.com/eng/Editorial/Daily-News/EU-Number-of-freelancers-grows-by-24-in-7-years-38211?&quot;&gt;24% in Europe&lt;/a&gt; – and the numbers keep growing. Who knows where this trend can drive us? Imagine a world where workers are no longer employed by a single company, but provide services for different companies according to the business needs and their competencies. Of course this situation would require some evolutions in terms of freelance security and rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/critisism_millenials.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Ways Of Working Between Generations&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this futuristic world, managers are conductors of a multi-located team of workers. They have to get everyone aligned with the company’s strategic objectives and working towards the same goal, despite their time engagement on the project (a few hours, a few days per week, …). Managers will have to leverage new technologies and communication tools in order to share the company culture and foster a sense of belonging to the company. Understanding individual aspirations and feelings will be crucial to the overall performance of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managers, be prepared: your job is about to change drastically.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special thanks to our hipster friends, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tristanlaffontas/&quot;&gt;Tristan Laffontas&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/noullet/&quot;&gt;Nicolas Noullet&lt;/a&gt;, for their feedback on this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 14:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
