<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TeamMood&#39;s Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.teammood.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://blog.teammood.com/</link>
    <description>Some words about feeling good at work.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 21:11:30 +0200</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Employee Recognition in the Workplace</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/recognition/workplace/tips/2013/10/22/the-importance-of-employee-recognition-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/recognition/workplace/tips/2013/10/22/the-importance-of-employee-recognition-in-the-workplace.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Canadian HR Council&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, employee recognition is the “the acknowledgement of an individual or team’s behavior, effort and accomplishments that support the organization’s goals and values.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee recognition usually takes a couple of forms, either informal or formal. Informal recognition is very spontaneous and helps encouraging certain behaviors that you want to reinforce in the workplace. On the other hand, formal recognition takes place when employees or departments are rewarded for exceeding strategic goals and objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these can be instrumental in establishing a positive and supportive climate within your company. Let’s look at three reasons why every manager should adopt an employee recognition program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increase-employee-productivity-companywide&quot;&gt;Increase employee productivity companywide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By recognizing their good work, employees will be motivated to go above and beyond their call of duty. It drives them to outperform themselves, and always become better at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees who are constantly reminded that they are doing an extraordinary job also feel like they are participating in the overall success of your company. Therefore, they become intrinsically motivated about their job, which is proven to have a positive impact on their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A side benefit of employee recognition is that it dramatically increases employee competitiveness. When their colleagues are rewarded for their achievements, employees are likely to try harder and achieve even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;helps-retain-and-attract-talented-employees&quot;&gt;Helps retain and attract talented employees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee recognition programs can have a positive impact on turnover rates. Indeed, this human resources management tool is one of the best ways to retain existing employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stress in the workplace is extremely counterproductive, and encouraging your employees can help relieve it. In the short term, absenteeism will be reduced. In the long run, employment longevity will be maximized, therefore reducing expensive turnover costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, employee recognition will attract talented employees to work for your company. Many job seekers are attracted to companies that are ranked as some of the best places to work for. For example, Glassdoor&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; makes it incredibly easy for existing and former employees to review your firm—and they can potentially make or break your reputation as an employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increase-revenues-and-maximize-profitability&quot;&gt;Increase revenues and maximize profitability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that employee recognition will have a positive impact on your bottom line. Despite the time and effort put into an effective employee recognition program, the investment is unquestionably worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees who are intrinsically motivated by their job will achieve more in a shorter amount of time. Teamwork will be enhanced within and across departments. By establishing the right culture, employees will be inclined to share their innovative ideas to improve a particular process or create a brand new product. The possibilities are endless, and the upside potential for your bottom line is unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the importance of employee recognition, one must understand the psychology behind it. Whichever their level in the organizational chart, people like to be valued for their contribution. One of the components of an amazing workplace is the gratitude towards every single employee. Unfortunately, appreciation is often undervalued in organizations of all sizes. However, as one of the most powerful management technique, employee recognition should be a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button center&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=the-importance-of-employee-recognition-in-the-workplace&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_the-importance-of-employee-recognition-in-the-workplace&quot;&gt;I want to increase my employee engagement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hrcouncil.ca/hr-toolkit/keeping-people-employee-recognition.cfm&quot;&gt;http://hrcouncil.ca/hr-toolkit/keeping-people-employee-recognition.cfm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glassdoor.com/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.glassdoor.com/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Build your own niko-niko calendar</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/diy/2013/05/07/build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/diy/2013/05/07/build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you know what is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko/&quot;&gt;Niko-Niko practice&lt;/a&gt;, it is now time to build your own !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;materials&quot;&gt;Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The calendar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some stickers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A piece of paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can print some monthly calendars using this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vertex42.com/calendars/printable-calendars.html&quot;&gt;free service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vertex42.com/calendars/printable-calendars.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/printable-calendar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Printable calendar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, buy some stickers, take these ones for instance, which are available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Color-Coding-Labels-Inches-Stickers/dp/B00DRGXBIM/&quot;&gt;Amazon US&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/stickers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stickers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-build-it-&quot;&gt;Let’s build it !&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the piece of paper, put the stickers with their meaning, for example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;green: happy day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;yellow: good day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;orange:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;red / pink: hard day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just pin the calendar, with the stickers and the piece of paper at the exit of the team room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-now-&quot;&gt;And now ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let each team member put a sticker on the calendar at the end of each working day, and voila !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you’re too busy to build your own, take a look at our service : &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com/?utm_source=Build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog-Build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;, an easy way to get a glimpse of the happiness of your coworkers !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com/?utm_source=Build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog-Build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/logo-256px.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 14:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is the niko-niko ?</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/faq/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/faq/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko calendar is an Agile practice which aims to detect patterns of change of mood of a team over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/niko-niko.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;An example of Niko-niko calendar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technic is very easy: at the end of the day, each team member paste a sticker on a calendar to tell if he had a good day at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other word, you probably ever went back to home from work and feel that you had a bad day, or you did not feel “productive”. That’s a red sticker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, you’ll see some color being dominant, it will give an insight of the mood of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a good idea to take a look at the Niko-niko calendar during the Agile retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not exact science, it is just a simple tool to get some more informations about the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko calendar is also know as “happiness index”. Also note that “niko” means “smile” in the japanese language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mention of the Niko-niko calendar is from an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.jp/nikonikocalendar/index_en.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article from Akinori SAKATA in 2006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, if you work with remote teams, and if it is not possible to use a physical calendar in the room, take a look at our service : &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com/?utm_source=what-is-niko-niko&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog-what-is-niko-niko &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;, an easy way to get a glimpse of the happiness of your coworkers !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com/?utm_source=what-is-niko-niko&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog-what-is-niko-niko &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/logo-256px.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 21:57:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Great tool to polish your idea</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/the%20idea/tools/2013/04/19/great-tool-to-polish-your-idea.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/the%20idea/tools/2013/04/19/great-tool-to-polish-your-idea.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you search the Web for resources about entrepreneurship, (lean)startup and so on, you’ll find a lot of articles and advices, but it is very hard to know how to begin, and what’s could be your next move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember how I get on this when I was doing some research for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot;&gt;TeamMood project&lt;/a&gt;, but I found an awesome gold nugget : &lt;a href=&quot;http://startitup.co&quot;&gt;StartitUp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://startitup.co&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/startitup.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the Lean Startup, it helps me lot with valuable advices, and a lot of articles containing several samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very simple to use : you go through the step by step guide, answer some questions about your idea/team/competition etc… and it progressively builds your Lean Canvas and helps you to structure your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also note that these guys are expecting a lot of feedback, and they are super reactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have an idea, and you don’t know where to start, go on &lt;a href=&quot;http://startitup.co&quot;&gt;StartitUp&lt;/a&gt; !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 19:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Twitter effect</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/marketing/social%20media/2013/04/18/the-twitter-effect.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/marketing/social%20media/2013/04/18/the-twitter-effect.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At last, I finally “officially” launched the TeamMood project by using two announce ments through Twitter, this is the one in English (another one was made in French):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;fr&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guys, I&#39;m launching my first side-project !! &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/9h4lyIIMtc&quot; title=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot;&gt;teammood.com&lt;/a&gt;, feel free to share the love ;-) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%23teammood&quot;&gt;#teammood&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%23nikoniko&quot;&gt;#nikoniko&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%23happy&quot;&gt;#happy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nicolas Deverge (@ndeverge) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ndeverge/status/324860646296539136&quot;&gt;18 avril 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far so good, in just hour, I had 29 people who registred by giving their email for about 179 unique visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I also received many positive feedbacks from some people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that my first MVP has quite a good result, so now, I have to keep on the adventure !!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 15:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Idea</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/leanstartup/the%20idea/2013/03/31/the-idea.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/leanstartup/the%20idea/2013/03/31/the-idea.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I wanted to build a project of my own. On a daily basis, I give advices to IT companies about technologies, methodologies and strategies to build awesome products. And now it is my turn !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finally took the time to build my first side project: &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot; class=&quot;teammood&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt; !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/coming-soon.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not explain what the project is about in this post, I prefer to let you discover the idea through the very first MVP which is a simple “&lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot;&gt;coming soon&lt;/a&gt;” page and let you give me a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#109;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the idea scratched me since many months because I feel that it can bring a lot in some companies that I work with. But it took me a lot of time before starting to build something, probably because I thought that if I begin to do this, I’d have to pull it to the end, ie some kind of commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, I use LeanStartup to explore the idea, because I don’t know if it will be a good one and if people will be interested. So let’s learn with this first MVP and we’ll see :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 15:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
