<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TeamMood&#39;s Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.teammood.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://blog.teammood.com/</link>
    <description>Some words about feeling good at work.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 10:25:48 +0100</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wellbeing at Work: The Benefits of Happiness in the Workplace</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The world has never before seen such high levels of productivity – even in France with our 5 weeks of vacation – and it is very much a consequence of the digital revolution and the automatization of many tasks. But the side effects of this faster work pace are not always welcome: burnout, depression, lack of purpose… Is being “sick on the job” the scourge of our age?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing’s for sure: a good paycheck is no longer enough to attract and retain the best talent. And companies know this: chief happiness officers, stress management coaches, and wellbeing programs are emerging to improve happiness in the workplace. So, what is actually at stake?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;happiness-at-work-the-key-to-increased-productivity&quot;&gt;Happiness at work, the key to increased productivity?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers from the University of Warwick in the UK have actually validated the theory. In 2014, Pr. Andrew J. Oswald, Pr. Eugenio Proto, and Pr. Daniel Sgroi published the striking results of their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.warwick.ac.uk/fac/soc/economics/staff/eproto/workingpapers/happinessproductivity.pdf&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;happy people were found to be 12% more productive, while unhappy workers proved 10% less productive.&lt;/strong&gt; According to the three economists, “human happiness has large and positive causal effects on productivity. Positive emotions appear to invigorate human beings.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is true for individuals is all the more true for organizations. Companies that invest in employee support and satisfaction tend to succeed in fostering happier workers. And happy workers tend to work better with others, to have more energy, to be more creative, to fix problems instead of complaining about them, and to make better decisions overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proof is in the profit. In 2005, Jerome Dodson, the founder of Parnassus Investments, added a new branch to his activities: the Parnassus Workplace Fund, a mutual fund that invests exclusively in large American firms proven to have &lt;strong&gt;outstanding workplaces, where employees are really happy.&lt;/strong&gt; The kinds of firms that “genuinely cared about their employees as people, not just hired hands.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dodson scouted the country, not for the most promising companies, but for the companies that treated employees with profound respect and offered them ongoing training and personal development. Other criteria included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing a meaningful form of profit sharing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offering healthcare and retirement benefits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being supportive of working mothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happiness pays!&lt;/strong&gt; To Dodson’s delight, the Parnassus Workplace Fund proved immediately, enormously, and enduringly successful. Since the fund’s inception and for 8 years, it “has had returns over 4% better than the S&amp;amp;P Index every year.” I’m sure we’d all like to get the same yield!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(For those of you who are not familiar with market valuations, the Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s 500, is an American stock market index based on the market capitalizations of 500 large companies with common stock listed on the NYSE or NASDAQ. Now you know.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when the latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gallup.com/poll/165269/worldwide-employees-engaged-work.aspx&quot;&gt;Gallup&lt;/a&gt; study tells you that “only 13 percent of employees are engaged at work worldwide” it makes you wonder &lt;strong&gt;why happiness in the workplace isn’t a higher priority.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-boost-wellbeing-at-work&quot;&gt;How do you boost wellbeing at work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/building-joy-planning-plans.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sharing those results, you must be wondering: how can I boost employee engagement and happiness in my company?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there’s good news and bad news. The bad news is: you cannot impose happiness on your employees. They have their share of responsibility in their own happiness. However, you can still set up ground rules and working conditions that will help your employees and teammates blossom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;develop-a-culture-of-trust-and-transparency&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Develop a culture of trust and transparency…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… where your employees can share their doubts and flaws, ask questions, challenge one another.. Keeping people afraid of failing or of showing weakness is the best way to hinder creativity. Your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;show-gratitude-and-value-positive-intelligence&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Show gratitude and value positive intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead by example. To set up a culture of gratitude and kindness, just display these qualities. If you are convincing enough, your teammates will follow your lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;foster-empowerment-and-accountability&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foster empowerment and accountability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stay engaged, a worker needs to feel that his job matters, and to be recognized for it. Empowering each individual to carry out his or her own tasks, and praising the results is the best way &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.teammood.com/engagement/tips/2013/07/30/how-to-improve-the-employee-engagement-with-these-5-great-tips.html&quot;&gt;to boost employee engagement&lt;/a&gt; – which doesn’t mean disparaging them should they need help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;favor-breaks-and-downtime&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favor breaks and downtime&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what most people may think, procrastination is actually good for productivity. While at ease, our brain enters its default mode and starts processing and sorting out information. These default mode phases are essential to our brain. Promoting &lt;strong&gt;breaks and relaxation will boost your teammates’ productivity and creativity.&lt;/strong&gt; It will also lower stress and frustration. Once again, I’d advise you to lead by example. Take a real lunch break and invite your teammates to join you. Take the time for coffee breaks and talk about anything but work. You can even set up a space to meditate, nap or do some yoga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;launch-a-wellness-program&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Launch a wellness program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set up a healthy lunch or snacks program, sponsor gym membership, dedicate a room to yoga or fitness… Did you know that exercise actually stimulates endorphins (endorphins are neurotransmitters that induce a feeling of euphoria) (what better way to get happy?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s your turn to be creative. What are your top tips for improving well being at your workplace?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 09:33:53 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MoraleApp Is Shutting Down :-(</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/en/2016/10/05/moraleapp-is-shutting-down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/en/2016/10/05/moraleapp-is-shutting-down.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 5th 2016, &lt;a href=&quot;https://moraleapp.com/shutdown&quot;&gt;MoraleApp announced that they are shutting down their service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a sad news for their users that have to look for an alternative but also for TeamMood who lose a pretty great competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, TeamMood has worked hard and it is now possible to migrate from MoraleApp to TeamMood seamlessly, without loosing your historical data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to import your MoraleApp data into TeamMood, just register there: 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getdrip.com/forms/14519314/submissions/new&quot;&gt;https://www.getdrip.com/forms/14519314/submissions/new&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 21:14:13 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 (Easy) Ways to Boost Team Productivity!</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/en/2016/01/12/5-ways-to-boost-team-productivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/en/2016/01/12/5-ways-to-boost-team-productivity.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As studies have shown time and time again, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.warwick.ac.uk/newsandevents/pressreleases/new_study_shows/&quot;&gt;happy teams are productive teams&lt;/a&gt;. So if you want to boost your team’s productivity, team happiness is definitely one of the goals that you should be setting yourself. It’s not just a matter of teamwork. When people are happy­ they work better and faster, whether as a team &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/jessica-stillman/happiness-makes-your-brain-work-better.html&quot;&gt;or as individuals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now you know how to boost your team’s productivity. Make them happy. How do you make them happy? Here are a few ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;daily-meetings-contribute-to-wellbeing-at-work&quot;&gt;#1. Daily meetings contribute to wellbeing at work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily meetings (short daily meetings of course) are an excellent way to start off the day, and give your team a sense of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These meetings should be open to all, meaning that any team member can speak their mind and offer their own opinion. They can bring their own ideas to the table, and feel that they have a real and tangible contribution to the team’s work, and the company’s success as a whole. When people are ‘engaged’ like this in the company’s decisions, they are more dedicated, and yes, happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/daily_meeting.png&quot; alt=&quot;Daily meeting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, you can also have these meetups in the middle of the day, as that creates a nice little break for your team, and they can have a breather before going on with the rest of their day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;track-their-mood&quot;&gt;#2. Track their mood&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you should be aware of your team as individuals, tracking the mood of the entire team is invaluable. Of course if you see that one of your team members isn’t happy you should have a talk with them, and see if you can help them resolve any issues that they may be having, but being able to judge the overall mood of the team is an excellent way to head off any problems that might happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=5-easy-ways-to-boost-team-productivity&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_5-easy-ways-to-boost-team-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/teammood-main-en.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Track the mood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, if people are becoming unhappy simply because they don’t have a coffee machine (and yes, we’ve seen that happen ☺), recognizing the fact that this is causing the entire team to underperform helps find a solution. In this case, it’s easy (just buy a coffee machine), but still – tracking the team’s mood is what helped find the underlying cause of the unhappiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wanna try to follow the mood of your people, we have you covered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=5-easy-ways-to-boost-team-productivity&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_5-easy-ways-to-boost-team-productivity&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;positive-feedback&quot;&gt;#3. Positive feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want your team members to be happy and improve their wellbeing at work? Tell them you appreciate them! It is literally as simple as that. It’s amazing at how a few simple compliments – when deserved – will brighten someone’s day up, and turn them into a far happier (and productive) person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;show-how-to-prioritize&quot;&gt;#4. Show how to prioritize&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter if it’s the developers launching the product on time, the Sales team meeting their quota, or the IT guys getting through all their helpdesk tickets - Getting work done contributes to the team happiness. You can’t always do EVERYTHING, of course, but you can certainly get the most urgent stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/priority.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prioritiez&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how does the team to that? By prioritizing. But how does your team know what to prioritize? Is the login feature more important than the Facebook share feature? Is the negotiation with ACME company more important than finding a connection to &lt;a href=&quot;http://seinfeld.wikia.com/wiki/Vandelay_Industries&quot;&gt;Vandelay Industries&lt;/a&gt;? That’s where you come in. As the team manager, it’s your job to help the team understand what is more important, so they can start clearing the workload off their desks, and yes, feel more accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;delegation&quot;&gt;#5. Delegation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful teamwork – and one of the keys to happy teams – is delegation. You can’t do everything yourself, and you shouldn’t have to. Share responsibilities with your key workers, give tasks to individuals and share the workload in general with your team, and not only will it be easier for you to get your job done, they will feel more appreciated and trusted. And team members that feel like the team leader trusts them­ will try harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, you see that making people feeling better at the workplace can be pretty easily done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 12:33:11 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Les Facteurs Qui Influent Sur L’humeur Au Travail</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/fr/2015/10/15/les-facteurs-qui-influent-sur-lhumeur-au-travail.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/fr/2015/10/15/les-facteurs-qui-influent-sur-lhumeur-au-travail.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Adopter la positive attitude au bureau n’est pas toujours facile. À force de côtoyer les mêmes personnes dans les mêmes bureaux toute la semaine, on finit par voir les sourires disparaître sur les visages. La courbe de notre humeur vacille sans vraiment que nous en comprenions les raisons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quels sont les facteurs qui rentrent en compte dans notre humeur ? Comment cultiver la bonne humeur au travail ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lenvironnement-de-travail&quot;&gt;L’environnement de travail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L’environnement de travail est l’un des points les plus importants. Si vous êtes au bureau, regardez autour de vous. Votre espace de travail vous permet-il de travailler dans de bonnes conditions ? Avez-vous assez d’espace ? Êtes-vous installé confortablement ? Le niveau sonore n’est-il pas trop élevé ? La luminosité est-elle suffisante ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tous ces éléments mis bout à bout contribuent à votre bien-être, et donc votre bonne humeur au travail. Saviez-vous que la lumière vous met de bonne humeur et vous rend plus efficace au travail ? À contrario, le manque de lumière va vous faire sécréter en quantité trop importante l’hormone du sommeil : la mélatonine. Vous perdrez alors toute votre énergie et n’aurez qu’une seule envie… celle de rentrer chez vous et de dormir ! Les bienfaits de la lumière sont prouvés scientifiquement : pour lutter contre les dépressions saisonnières les médecins recommandent la luminothérapie. Cette thérapie par la lumière consiste à s’exposer quotidiennement à une lumière artificielle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/people-office-group-team.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Environnement de travail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vous savez ce qu’il vous reste à faire : faire vos pauses à l’extérieur pour faire le plein de lumière naturelle et vous équiper de lampes de bureau si l’éclairage est insuffisant !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Que ce soit par manque de lumière, d’espace ou de confort vous avez mille et une raisons de vous sentir mal au bureau. Ne restez pas frustré si vous pensez pouvoir être mieux installé que vous l’êtes actuellement ! Faites remonter vos remarques et suggestions à votre supérieur, abordez le problème en réunion ou prenez des initiatives si les choses ne changent pas ! Vos collègues, qui sont sûrement du même avis que vous, vous remercieront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lattitude-vis--vis-de-vos-collgues&quot;&gt;L’attitude vis à vis de vos collègues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dire bonjour au bureau : un geste anodin mais qui toutefois permet de débuter la journée sur une note positive ! Si ce n’est déjà le cas, n’hésitez pas à parcourir tous les bureaux pour prendre le temps de saluer vos collègues un à un.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Quoi de plus énervant que de se faire couper la parole ou de voir des collègues concentrés sur leur smartphone au moment où vous prenez la parole en réunion ? Soyez vous-même exemplaire : n’envoyez pas de texto en réunion, sentez-vous impliqué par ce qui est en train de se passer. Des règles élémentaires certes, mais qu’il n’est pas inutile de rappeler…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Aidez vos collègues : n’hésitez pas à rendre un coup de pouce à vos collègues et à vous entraider. Ils vous le rendront bien le jour où vous aurez besoin d’eux. Vous tisserez ainsi des liens avec vos collègues en partageant ces moments un peu informels.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Prenez le temps pour déjeuner avec vos collègues. Vous avez la manie de déjeuner derrière votre écran ou d’avaler un sandwich en cinq minutes entre deux rendez-vous ?  Vous devriez arrêter ! Il est prouvé que les déjeuners pris ensemble permettent de souder les équipes ! Ce sont des moments privilégiés pour échanger avec vos collègues autour de sujets autre que le travail (sisi, on vous promet ça fait du bien de temps en temps !)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/people-coffee-tea-meeting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Collaboration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soyez-vous-mme-positif&quot;&gt;Soyez vous-même positif&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Un problème de transport, une météo déplorable… de quoi vous mettre en rogne ! Même si de nombreux facteurs externes jouent sur votre humeur vous êtes le seul maître de votre humeur. Vous ne devez pas céder à l’envie de râler à tout bout de champ dès que quelque chose ne va pas. En vous plaignant, vos collègues ressentent de l’empathie pour vous et s’imaginent à votre place. De ce fait, ils se sentent mal à leur tour. Attention donc à ne pas plomber l’ambiance générale avec vos soucis quotidiens.
Si vous ne dégagez pas quelque chose de positif, vos collègues vous fuiront et voudront passer le moins de temps possible à vos côtés. En râlant, c’est aussi sur votre propre moral que vous agissez.  En étant positif vous vous entourerez de personnes elles-mêmes positives : un vrai cercle vertueux !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bref&quot;&gt;Bref…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La bonne humeur au travail est avant tout un état d’esprit auquel chacun d’entre nous doit s’exercer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tous les chefs d’entreprise aspirent à une ambiance générale qui puisse satisfaire ceux qui travaillent dans l’entreprise afin d’éviter des démissions trop régulières liées à une mauvaise ambiance. Ces démissions pourraient être néfastes pour l’entreprise à long terme : elles sont un vrai gouffre financier pour l’entreprise qui doit continuellement recruter et former de nouveaux salariés. Autant d’argent qui aurait pu être investi pour améliorer le bien-être des salariés.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultiver la bonne humeur au travail : vous avez tout à y gagner !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 11:35:51 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TeamMood Now On Your Wall</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/features/tips/2015/07/30/teammood-now-on-your-wall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/features/tips/2015/07/30/teammood-now-on-your-wall.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/dashboard_monitor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard Monitor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a contribution by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nrichand&quot;&gt;Nathaniel Richand&lt;/a&gt; (a TeamMood power user), it is now possible to display the latest moods of your team on your monitoring display in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He wrote a widget for &lt;a href=&quot;http://dashing.io/&quot;&gt;Dashing&lt;/a&gt;, a great and easy to use free dashboard framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TeamMood widget looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/teammood_widget.png&quot; alt=&quot;TeamMood Widget&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use it and don’t forget to send us pictures ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/nrichand/265342903eabc4ad0050&quot;&gt;Go get the widget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 15:47:39 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Effectively Remove Google Analytics Spam</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/tech/2014/12/13/how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/tech/2014/12/13/how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since several months, you certainly have seen some strange referral sources in your Google Analytics reports. Those are spam:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/spam.png&quot; alt=&quot;Spam in Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have several ways to avoid this, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;using segment by excluding these domains in Google Analytics reports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;excluding these domains in Google Analytics filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you have to know which domains to exclude for both methods, and they are evolving everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most effective way I found is to only include traffic that go to your website (the spam does not really go on your website, they just mess with the Google Analytics API).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that, just go to the Google Analytics Admin Panel, and choose “Filter”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/ga_admin.png&quot; alt=&quot;Filters in Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then add a new filter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/ga_filters.png&quot; alt=&quot;Add a new filter in Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the last steps are to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;choose a name for your filter, such as “Exclude Spam”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;select “Custom”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;click “Include”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;choose “Hostname” in the “Filter field”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in the “Filter Pattern” field, use the following syntax &lt;code&gt;.*teammood.com| translate.googleusercontent.com&lt;/code&gt; and replace &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam&quot;&gt;teammood.com&lt;/a&gt; by your domain name (Google Translate is there in case people are using it to translate your page with Chrome).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/ga_remove_spam.png&quot; alt=&quot;Remove Spam in Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will not remove the old spam, but from now, the spam will not ever be recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this tip made your day? If so, take a look at how TeamMood is helping teams to have better days :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam&quot;&gt;Discover TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 07:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Employee Recognition in the Workplace</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/recognition/workplace/tips/2013/10/22/the-importance-of-employee-recognition-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/recognition/workplace/tips/2013/10/22/the-importance-of-employee-recognition-in-the-workplace.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Canadian HR Council&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, employee recognition is the “the acknowledgement of an individual or team’s behavior, effort and accomplishments that support the organization’s goals and values.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee recognition usually takes a couple of forms, either informal or formal. Informal recognition is very spontaneous and helps encouraging certain behaviors that you want to reinforce in the workplace. On the other hand, formal recognition takes place when employees or departments are rewarded for exceeding strategic goals and objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these can be instrumental in establishing a positive and supportive climate within your company. Let’s look at three reasons why every manager should adopt an employee recognition program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increase-employee-productivity-companywide&quot;&gt;Increase employee productivity companywide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By recognizing their good work, employees will be motivated to go above and beyond their call of duty. It drives them to outperform themselves, and always become better at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees who are constantly reminded that they are doing an extraordinary job also feel like they are participating in the overall success of your company. Therefore, they become intrinsically motivated about their job, which is proven to have a positive impact on their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A side benefit of employee recognition is that it dramatically increases employee competitiveness. When their colleagues are rewarded for their achievements, employees are likely to try harder and achieve even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;helps-retain-and-attract-talented-employees&quot;&gt;Helps retain and attract talented employees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee recognition programs can have a positive impact on turnover rates. Indeed, this human resources management tool is one of the best ways to retain existing employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stress in the workplace is extremely counterproductive, and encouraging your employees can help relieve it. In the short term, absenteeism will be reduced. In the long run, employment longevity will be maximized, therefore reducing expensive turnover costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, employee recognition will attract talented employees to work for your company. Many job seekers are attracted to companies that are ranked as some of the best places to work for. For example, Glassdoor&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; makes it incredibly easy for existing and former employees to review your firm—and they can potentially make or break your reputation as an employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increase-revenues-and-maximize-profitability&quot;&gt;Increase revenues and maximize profitability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that employee recognition will have a positive impact on your bottom line. Despite the time and effort put into an effective employee recognition program, the investment is unquestionably worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees who are intrinsically motivated by their job will achieve more in a shorter amount of time. Teamwork will be enhanced within and across departments. By establishing the right culture, employees will be inclined to share their innovative ideas to improve a particular process or create a brand new product. The possibilities are endless, and the upside potential for your bottom line is unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the importance of employee recognition, one must understand the psychology behind it. Whichever their level in the organizational chart, people like to be valued for their contribution. One of the components of an amazing workplace is the gratitude towards every single employee. Unfortunately, appreciation is often undervalued in organizations of all sizes. However, as one of the most powerful management technique, employee recognition should be a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hrcouncil.ca/hr-toolkit/keeping-people-employee-recognition.cfm&quot;&gt;http://hrcouncil.ca/hr-toolkit/keeping-people-employee-recognition.cfm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glassdoor.com/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.glassdoor.com/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Improve the Employee Engagement With These 5 Great Tips</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/engagement/tips/2013/07/30/how-to-improve-the-employee-engagement-with-these-5-great-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/engagement/tips/2013/07/30/how-to-improve-the-employee-engagement-with-these-5-great-tips.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Each company works hard towards improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time pass by, business keeps on improving and keeps on growing which opens great chances of hiring people. These people will play a big role for the growth of the business. Being an employee, you must possess a qualification that each company requires. You must be a happy people, willing to do the work, begin the engagement as an action not as survey, and you must know how to engage yourself from the bottom and not to the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we say employee engagement, these are managing people who are fully involved in a company who are being very enthusiastic about their work. They care about the future of the company they are working for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-how-bosses-really-enhance-employee-engagement&quot;&gt;But how bosses really enhance employee engagement?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with the leaders or the founders of the company. Since they are the head of the company, they should help their employees to learn how to be engaged in their work. They must show that they value their employees. They should provide challenging work with career advancement and communicate clear vision to the employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognition&lt;/strong&gt; to the job well done is big help. In many companies, recognition and financial rewards are joined at hip. By means of this, employees become more motivated to do their work and become more productive. Recognition is a key tool to make your employee opt for extra effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomy&lt;/strong&gt; at work helps the employee to set their own schedules. They have the right to decide how they are going to do their work. Using these methods helps employee to become more productive and happier at work. Having this option helps them to fulfill the work because they have freedom to make decision. Employers give parameters and suggest choices. This make the employee give a dedicated level of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Company employee also needs respect. &lt;strong&gt;Respect&lt;/strong&gt; is a form of showing a regards or concern to the workers. Treating the employee with right attitude is good to help them feel that they belong in the company they are working for. Managers can show respect by means of several ways such as dealing with people with courtesy and kindness, encourage to express opinion and ideas, and never insult people in front of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why is it that employees need to be engaged at work? There is a good objective that the team wants to achieve. &lt;strong&gt;Pointing out your purpose&lt;/strong&gt; help you find out why. Maybe you want to become more successful, you want to inspire your family or you want to bring hopes in your community; these things will help you to have your own purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a &lt;strong&gt;good facilitator&lt;/strong&gt; in managing a company is also a scalable approach to making every detail of the task well streamlined thus maximizing efficiency and resolving conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the tips above will help you become a good example. At the same time, it will create a better result of being productive at work. Above all, dedication and strategic management are keys to reach success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 17:43:42 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Build your own niko-niko calendar</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/diy/2013/05/07/build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/diy/2013/05/07/build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you know what is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko/&quot;&gt;Niko-Niko practice&lt;/a&gt;, it is now time to build your own !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;materials&quot;&gt;Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The calendar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some stickers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A piece of paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can print some monthly calendars using this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vertex42.com/calendars/printable-calendars.html&quot;&gt;free service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vertex42.com/calendars/printable-calendars.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/printable-calendar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Printable calendar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, buy some stickers, take these ones for instance, which are available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Color-Coding-Labels-Inches-Stickers/dp/B00DRGXBIM/&quot;&gt;Amazon US&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/stickers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stickers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-build-it-&quot;&gt;Let’s build it !&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the piece of paper, put the stickers with their meaning, for example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;green: happy day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;yellow: good day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;orange:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;red / pink: hard day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just pin the calendar, with the stickers and the piece of paper at the exit of the team room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-now-&quot;&gt;And now ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let each team member put a sticker on the calendar at the end of each working day, and voila !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you’re too busy to build your own, take a look at our service : &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com/?utm_source=Build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog-Build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;, an easy way to get a glimpse of the happiness of your coworkers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 14:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is the niko-niko ?</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/faq/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/faq/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko calendar is an Agile practice which aims to detect patterns of change of mood of a team over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/niko-niko.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;An example of Niko-niko calendar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technic is very easy: at the end of the day, each team member paste a sticker on a calendar to tell if he had a good day at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other word, you probably ever went back to home from work and feel that you had a bad day, or you did not feel “productive”. That’s a red sticker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, you’ll see some color being dominant, it will give an insight of the mood of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a good idea to take a look at the Niko-niko calendar during the Agile retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not exact science, it is just a simple tool to get some more informations about the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko calendar is also know as “happiness index”. Also note that “niko” means “smile” in the japanese language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mention of the Niko-niko calendar is from an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.jp/nikonikocalendar/index_en.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article from Akinori SAKATA in 2006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, if you work with remote teams, and if it is not possible to use a physical calendar in the room, take a look at our service : &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com/?utm_source=what-is-niko-niko&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog-what-is-niko-niko &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;, an easy way to get a glimpse of the happiness of your coworkers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 21:57:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Great tool to polish your idea</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/the%20idea/tools/2013/04/19/great-tool-to-polish-your-idea.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/the%20idea/tools/2013/04/19/great-tool-to-polish-your-idea.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you search the Web for resources about entrepreneurship, (lean)startup and so on, you’ll find a lot of articles and advices, but it is very hard to know how to begin, and what’s could be your next move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember how I get on this when I was doing some research for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot;&gt;TeamMood project&lt;/a&gt;, but I found an awesome gold nugget : &lt;a href=&quot;http://startitup.co&quot;&gt;StartitUp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://startitup.co&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/startitup.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the Lean Startup, it helps me lot with valuable advices, and a lot of articles containing several samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very simple to use : you go through the step by step guide, answer some questions about your idea/team/competition etc… and it progressively builds your Lean Canvas and helps you to structure your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also note that these guys are expecting a lot of feedback, and they are super reactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have an idea, and you don’t know where to start, go on &lt;a href=&quot;http://startitup.co&quot;&gt;StartitUp&lt;/a&gt; !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=great-tool-to-polish-your-idea&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_great-tool-to-polish-your-idea&quot;&gt;I want to discover TeamMood !&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 19:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Twitter effect</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/marketing/social%20media/2013/04/18/the-twitter-effect.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/marketing/social%20media/2013/04/18/the-twitter-effect.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At last, I finally “officially” launched the TeamMood project by using two announce ments through Twitter, this is the one in English (another one was made in French):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;fr&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guys, I&#39;m launching my first side-project !! &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/9h4lyIIMtc&quot; title=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot;&gt;teammood.com&lt;/a&gt;, feel free to share the love ;-) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%23teammood&quot;&gt;#teammood&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%23nikoniko&quot;&gt;#nikoniko&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search/%23happy&quot;&gt;#happy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Nicolas Deverge (@ndeverge) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ndeverge/status/324860646296539136&quot;&gt;18 avril 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far so good, in just hour, I had 29 people who registred by giving their email for about 179 unique visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I also received many positive feedbacks from some people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that my first MVP has quite a good result, so now, I have to keep on the adventure !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=the-twitter-effect&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_the-twitter-effect&quot;&gt;I want to discover TeamMood !&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 15:23:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Idea</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/leanstartup/the%20idea/2013/03/31/the-idea.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/leanstartup/the%20idea/2013/03/31/the-idea.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I wanted to build a project of my own. On a daily basis, I give advices to IT companies about technologies, methodologies and strategies to build awesome products. And now it is my turn !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finally took the time to build my first side project: &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot; class=&quot;teammood&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt; !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/coming-soon.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not explain what the project is about in this post, I prefer to let you discover the idea through the very first MVP which is a simple “&lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com&quot;&gt;coming soon&lt;/a&gt;” page and let you give me a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#109;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#100;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the idea scratched me since many months because I feel that it can bring a lot in some companies that I work with. But it took me a lot of time before starting to build something, probably because I thought that if I begin to do this, I’d have to pull it to the end, ie some kind of commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, I use LeanStartup to explore the idea, because I don’t know if it will be a good one and if people will be interested. So let’s learn with this first MVP and we’ll see :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=the-idea&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_the-idea&quot;&gt;I want to discover TeamMood !&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 15:07:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
