<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TeamMood&#39;s Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.teammood.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://blog.teammood.com/</link>
    <description>Some words about feeling good at work.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 15:46:04 +0100</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Simple Guide to Run Agile Retrospectives</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/2018/02/07/a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/2018/02/07/a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In our ever-evolving environment, we hear more and more about Scrum, XP, and other Agile methods. If they have their differences, they all have in common one principle: teams must adapt over time and continuously improve the way they work. And &lt;strong&gt;retrospectives&lt;/strong&gt; are the cornerstone to this principle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-a-retrospective&quot;&gt;What is a retrospective?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a context of continuous improvement, a retrospective helps team members improve the way they work together based on the past weeks’ events. During a retrospective, the team reflects on what happened in the timeframe and identifies actions for improvement going forward. It lays halfway between between lessons learned and an action plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may wonder: &lt;em&gt;do I really need retrospectives&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you may think your team organization is already optimized, you probably don’t realize some of the issues and frustrations your teammates encounter daily. Taking the time to discuss them and find solutions is key to improve the way your team works, and overall to improve your productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/are-you-too-busy-to-improve2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Too Busy To Improve: use retrospectives to reflect on your process&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-does-a-retrospective-work&quot;&gt;How does a retrospective work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of formats of retrospectives, and none that you should adopt for good – otherwise it will become too repetitive and end up being inefficient. But whatever the format, it should always include 2 axes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Celebrate successes&lt;/strong&gt;: a new client, a feature release, …&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discuss the issues and irritants&lt;/strong&gt; – from the smallest (the coffee is bad) to the biggest (we need new fundings)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective is to identify the 2 or 3 most urging and important issues, define some actions to solve them and distribute them among the teammates. At the next retrospective, people will share their feedback: were they able to put the measures in place? Have they had a positive impact? If not, should we insist or give up? And the cycle goes on. In this type of organization, the manager is no longer the only one responsible for making his or her team happy and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrospectives usually last for half an hour to one hour, and occur at the end of a cycle or iteration – ideally every two weeks, at most every month. And should include all team members: it’s the collective that makes it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tools-to-make-your-retrospective-work-better&quot;&gt;3 tools to make your retrospective work better&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of tools available there, those are the ones we enjoy the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;retromathttpsplans-for-retrospectivescomen--to-get-inspiration-on-retrospective-formats&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plans-for-retrospectives.com/en/&quot;&gt;Retromat&lt;/a&gt; – to get inspiration on retrospective formats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said earlier, it’s better to use a new format for each of your retrospectives in order to maintain their efficiency. Retromat helps you find inspiration for your retrospectives. You can browse around or select a random plan, change it to fit the team’s situation, print it and share the URL to your teammates. It’s that easy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;retriumhttpswwwretriumcom--to-run-retrospectives-with-distributed-teams&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.retrium.com/&quot;&gt;Retrium&lt;/a&gt; – to run retrospectives with distributed teams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrospectives are even more important for multi-located teams – and at the same time more difficult to run. If you are managing a distributed team, you should consider using a tool like Retrium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrium is a web-app that helps you run your retrospectives. It provides you with the tools and methodology to run effective retrospectives and identify concrete, outside-of-the-box ideas on how to improve the way you work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being online, Retrium helps you organize your retrospective even with a distributed team. Everyone has access to the ideas and comments their colleagues shared. It provides the opportunity for teammates to bring up topics that would normally stay buried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teammoodhttpswwwteammoodcomutmsourceblogutmmediumpostutmcontenta-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectivesutmcampaignbloga-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives--to-get-topics-from-the-teammates-to-discuss-about&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt; – to get topics from the teammates to discuss about&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not us, it’s our clients who say it! If you run retrospectives every two weeks or every month, it’s hard to remember everything that happened during this timeframe. You usually end up focusing on the last few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With TeamMood, you can have access to daily feedback and comments from your team members during the whole period. It works as a team’s diary. Using this data during your retrospectives helps you get a comprehensive view of what happened, and enriches or starts interesting  discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_a-simple-guide-to-run-agile-retrospectives&quot;&gt;Discover TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 15:16:35 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best Practices From Our Users</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/2017/12/06/best-practices-from-our-users.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/2017/12/06/best-practices-from-our-users.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is good, but you still need to act on it. Many of our customers have asked us advice on how to make the best use of the data collected thanks to TeamMood. So, here comes a compilation of the best practices to leverage TeamMood and have a real impact on your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;giving-the-floor-to-team-members-during-daily-meetings&quot;&gt;Giving the floor to team members during daily meetings…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to our users, one of the great advantages of TeamMood is its daily tracking. Other similar tools work weekly or monthly, which is not enough to really track the mood of your team and follow trends. And once you track the mood of your team daily, you can share the results daily too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathaniel is an agile coach who intervenes as a consultant in different IT teams. He uses TeamMood during his daily meetings in order to talk openly about the bad moods and comments. It triggers the discussions and helps the team quickly find a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another client of ours also started to share daily the results from the previous day, an average and the overall trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;body&quot;&gt; “During our daily meeting, people started to speak up and explain the reasons behind a certain grade or comment. It released the floor and initiated dialog among the team.”&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Guillaume&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-lightening-up-the-mood&quot;&gt;… and lightening up the mood&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TeamMood doesn’t have to be all serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/laughing.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our clients, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guestonline.io/&quot;&gt;GuestOnline&lt;/a&gt;, created a game based on TeamMood’s results. At the end of some particularly long meetings, to relax everyone, they share some of the comments from TeamMood and make a quiz ‘guess who wrote this comment’. They also invented a variant to this game at the end of summer, with holiday pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;body&quot;&gt; “At the beginning, I felt the team was a bit feebleness, but after a while it became a time of relaxing and fun at the end of a big meeting. Everyone participates, and sometimes people share the story behind a certain mood. We all have a good time and finish the meeting on a positive and happy note :)”&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Emilie, GuestOnline&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-retrospectives&quot;&gt;Improving retrospectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/postits.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running retrospectives with your teammates on a regular basis is crucial to learn from past mistakes and try to do better. That’s why the best companies take the time to review past projects, analyse what went wrong or could be improved upon, and share new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you run retrospectives every week, two weeks of every months, it’s hard to remember everything that happened during your timeframe. Without a tool like TeamMood, your retrospectives end up focusing on the past few days, leaving aside older events or issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to TeamMood, you can have access to daily feedback and comments from your team members. Your retrospective are richer and more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-teammood-as-a-management-tool&quot;&gt;Using TeamMood as a management tool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than the result of the daily poll on itself, what is important is how you react on it. Indeed, TeamMood provides managers with data and feedback to gauge their team’s feeling and well-being, but they still have to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jean-Baptiste, an IT manager at a big French retail outfit company, shares: “I don’t just look at the score for each team. What’s more important is to see how a Scrum Master responds and helps the team navigate their way through any problems that arise.” (Read the full story &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/en/success/Success-story-scrum-masters-en.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;identifying-the-most-urging-topics&quot;&gt;Identifying the most urging topics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TeamMood doesn’t provide just a grade but also gives the opportunity for team members to share a comment, providing more context or information on a specific issue. In order to identify the most urging topic, one of our clients, working in a research company, classifies the daily comments by category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, he can directly pinpoint his efforts to the most recurring and urging topics, and relieve his teammates of their issues. It helps him identify trends on different topics, for instance a need in recruitment or a tight deadline. It also gives him insights to whether the subject has been addressed and solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=TeamMood%20is%20a%20true%20managerial%20help.%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/12/06/best-practices-from-our-users.html&quot;&gt;
    “TeamMood is a true managerial help.”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 10:55:44 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Defuse Conflicts at Work in 5 Steps</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/2017/06/29/how-to-defuse-conflicts-at-work-in-5-steps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/2017/06/29/how-to-defuse-conflicts-at-work-in-5-steps.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2017/04/11/8-warnings-that-a-crisis-is-looming-among-your-teammates.html&quot;&gt;identified the signs of an upcoming conflict at work&lt;/a&gt;, you need to resolve it before it burst. I’m going to kill the dream right away: conflicts don’t resolve by themselves. You have to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts are sensitive subjects for most people, whether they fight it or decide to flight. Some cultures even find it rude and disrespectful to disagree or oppose someone, especially at work, in a situation of hierarchy. Wouldn’t be easier to consider conflicts like any other problem to be solved, with a specific methodology? You’re in luck, we’ve gathered all the literature on the topic to craft you the perfect guide to solve conflicts at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take an example. You’ve recently been hired to handle a 2-year project that just started. The team seems nice overall, but you feel some resistance from one of the members – let’s call him Alex. Rumours warn you that this person was actually seeking this position, but even if he was showing a lot of enthusiasm, the management decided he wasn’t senior enough so his application was turned down. How do you handle it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/handshake.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;talk-about-the-conflict&quot;&gt;1 - Talk about the conflict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t say it enough, communication is key. I’m not talking about warning the whole company or complain at every coffee break. On the contrary, communication should always be respectful and constructive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Communication%20should%20always%20be%20respectful%20and%20constructive%20at%20the%20workplace.%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/06/29/how-to-defuse-conflicts-at-work-in-5-steps.html&quot;&gt;
    “Communication should always be respectful and constructive at the workplace.”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our example, I would first try to gather information about Alex from your own boss and/or the person that hired you (and not him). Try to get feedback on the way he usually acts within a team, what he likes or dislikes… but be subtle or people will ask questions and the entire company may end up getting involved in the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you should talk to the interested party. Again, subtility is the rule, you don’t want him to feel attacked. Putting a situation of conflict into words is always a good start to resolving it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try something like: “Alex, I have felt some resistance from your part [or even aggressivity if applicable], am I misinterpreting or is there something we should talk about?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;put-yourself-in-the-other-persons-shoes&quot;&gt;2 - Put yourself in the other person’s shoes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a situation of conflict, every part feels in its own right and tends to defend his or her position. As a result, your empathy for the other one will most certainly fall to its lowest. In order to start moving the lines and restore some empathy in the relationship, start by putting yourself in the other person’s shoes, and ask him or her to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if it’s not directly your fault – you’re not the one who made the decision to hire yourself – it’s very easy to imagine why Alex would feel reluctant about you. You embody both his dream and his failure. Wouldn’t you feel the same if you were him?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Empathy%20is%20key%20to%20conflict%20resolution.%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/06/29/how-to-defuse-conflicts-at-work-in-5-steps.html&quot;&gt;
    “Empathy is key to conflict resolution.”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t stop there, ask him to do the same: “I understand your situation. Now, could I ask you to do the same for me? I’m new in this project and this company, and this position means a lot to me. How would you feel if you were me? I really need all of project team members to be 100% onboard.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-the-very-person-involved-in-this-conflict-to-find-a-solution&quot;&gt;3 - Ask the very person involved in this conflict to find a solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you define a solution on your side, chances are that the person involved won’t fully agree or apply them. You want this person to get his or her hands “dirty” in solving the conflict – it’s much harder to reject something you first agreed on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our example, simply ask Alex what would make him feel better about this project. Maybe working closer to you would get him the experience he was originally lacking to handle the project. Or on the contrary, giving him more responsibility would make him more comfortable to learn and grow. Another project may be coming up, on which you could refer him based on the first months working together – on the condition that he actually gets better involved. Agreeing on a solution will immediately make things easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;call-on-a-third-person&quot;&gt;4 - Call on a third person&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t handle the situation by yourself, you should seek out from some help. The key here is to call in somebody that both parties respect and trust (if possible, outside of your direct hierarchy). In some companies, one person (or more) is in charge of employee protection and social dialogue. While bound to professional and with total neutrality, this person can help you reach a settlement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Putting%20a%20situation%20of%20conflict%20into%20words%20is%20always%20a%20good%20start%20to%20resolving%20it.%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/06/29/how-to-defuse-conflicts-at-work-in-5-steps.html&quot;&gt;
    “Putting a situation of conflict into words is always a good start to resolving it.”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other cases, management or the HR department might offer you the services of an external mediator. Being external (and hence neutral) to the organization, a mediator will have better chances of resolving the conflict – if he or she succeeds in gaining the two parties’ trust. Indeed, the mediator’s ultimate role is to do anything and everything necessary to assist parties to reach an agreement, by educating them, questioning and clarifying the situation, remembering the roles and responsibilities of each individual, etc. However, he or she can’t define a settlement by him/herself, the persons involved in the conflict ultimately have to find an agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;move-on-from-the-conflict&quot;&gt;5 - Move on from the conflict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve done all of the above and nothing’s worked, the solution may be for one of the two people involved to move on: go and work in another department, or even leave the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said before, Alex might be interested in working on this new project that is about to start. Or on the contrary, agree to leave with a comfortable package from the company. Beware: the risk there is to set the example of bad behavior getting people what they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts should be handled with diligence yet precaution. The good thing about a conflict is that when overtaken, it can create an even better work relationship, based on communication and trust. But in order to reach this situation, you must act with kindness and respect, and inspire the other person to do so: those are the principles of &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/power-up-your-team-with-nonviolent-communication-principles/&quot;&gt;NonViolent Communication&lt;/a&gt;, a communication process I strongly encourage you to go into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop fearing conflicts and start handling them!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 14:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Exclusive Tools to Make Your Teammates Happier at Work</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
“Work it harder, make it better, do it faster, makes us stronger
&lt;br /&gt;
More than ever, hour after, our work is never over&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;[Ante-scriptum: This article is best read while listening to Daft Punk]&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Society, our bosses, and even Daft Punk tell us to work harder and be more productive, at any cost. In recent years, however, companies have begun to realize that &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html&quot;&gt;productivity at any cost can be unproductive&lt;/a&gt;. To remedy this, they have started to introduce greater flexibility and more perks at the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are on the same wavelength and eager to enhance the well-being at your office, here is our selection of exclusive tools and startups that you’ll soon find indispensable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;goodco--find-your-match&quot;&gt;Good&amp;amp;Co – find your match&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hiring process is always a sensitive subject for companies. It can be long and costly, especially if the candidate you end up hiring turns out not to be the right fit for the company. The best candidate is not just the smartest or the most creative person, but the one who best complements your company and your current employees, and who makes your team stronger ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://good.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/8-tools/good-co.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://good.co/&quot;&gt;Good&amp;amp;Co&lt;/a&gt; is half matchmaker, half headhunter. Based on a proprietary psychometric algorithm, the platform helps job seekers identify their core strengths and professional persona, to assess whether they’ll be a good fit for a company. As the founders say, “It’s only when a job feels like it was made for you that work feels less like work and more like play. Productivity and success follow naturally”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Get%20the%20best%20candidates%20for%20YOUR%20company%20with%20@ingoodco%20%23wellbeingatwork%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html&quot;&gt;
    “Get the best candidates for YOUR company with @ingoodco #wellbeingatwork”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;icescrum--get-your-company-to-the-next-agile-step&quot;&gt;iceScrum – get your company to the next (agile) step&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to do it faster, make it more flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever your company’s current level of organizational agility, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icescrum.com/&quot;&gt;iceScrum&lt;/a&gt; is the project management software for you. Based on the pillars of scrum (transparency, inspection, and adaptation), it allows you to get a global overview of your project, and it automatically produces analyses and calculates productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.icescrum.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/8-tools/Icescrum.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iceScrum integrates with the tools essential to the success of your projects: Jira, Github, Slack… It also helps your teammates collaborate on projects across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Get%20your%20company%20to%20the%20next%20agile%20step%20with%20@icescrum%20%23agile%20%23productivity%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html&quot;&gt;
    “Get your company to the next agile step with @icescrum #agile #productivity”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;weekdone--turn-planning-and-goal-setting-into-a-game&quot;&gt;Weekdone – turn planning and goal setting into a game&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weekdone.com/&quot;&gt;Weekdone&lt;/a&gt;, you can make achieving goals feel like a game. Weekdone lets you create, share, and assign objectives at company, department, team, and individual levels so that everyone will be on the same page. Teammates can share information and help each other, using a straightforward and elegant interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.weekdone.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/8-tools/weekdone.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need another reason? Weekdone uses the same Objective and Key Results (OKR) methodology used by world-leading companies such as Google, LinkedIn and Twitter – and we know they just can’t be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Turn%20planning%20and%20goal%20setting%20into%20a%20game%20with%20@weekdone%20%23productivity%20%23funatwork%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html&quot;&gt;
    “Turn planning and goal setting into a game with @weekdone #productivity #funatwork”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;noisli--boost-productivity--with-noise&quot;&gt;Noisli – boost productivity … with noise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that noise can actually be better for productivity than total silence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may feel counter-intuitive, but studies show that productivity levels are higher when people are working in a coffee shop surrounded by a background buzz of conversation than in a quiet, empty room. But the level of noise has to be just right – a bar playing Daft Punk as loud as in a club may not be so effective, with the exception being the writing of this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.noisli.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/8-tools/noisli.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noisli.com/&quot;&gt;Noisli&lt;/a&gt; is a background noise generator that helps drown out annoying noises and lets you create your ideal environment for working and relaxing. Whether it be the sound of the wind, raindrops, fire, or the actual background noise of a coffee shop, you can choose the atmosphere that will make you focus best and boost your productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Boost%20your%20productivity%20at%20work%20with%20noise%20@noisli%20%23wellbeing%20%23productivity%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html&quot;&gt;
    “Boost your productivity at work with noise @noisli #wellbeing #productivity”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;retrium--learn-from-your-failures-and-successes&quot;&gt;Retrium – learn from your failures and successes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What doesn’t kill you makes you stronger… this is true if you actually learn from your mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why the best companies take the time to review past projects, analyse what went wrong or could be improved upon, and share new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.retrium.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/8-tools/retrium.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.retrium.com/&quot;&gt;Retrium&lt;/a&gt; gives you the tools and methodology to run effective retrospectives and identify concrete, outside-of-the-box ideas on how to improve the way you work. It provides the space and opportunity for teammates to bring up topics that would normally stay buried – and teams love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=.@RetriumHQ,%20a%20retrospective%20tool%20your%20team%20will%20love%20%23wellbeingatwork%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html&quot;&gt;
    “.@RetriumHQ, a retrospective tool your team will love #wellbeingatwork”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;teammood--discover-your-team-members-most-secret-thoughts&quot;&gt;TeamMood – discover your team members’ most secret thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Sorry if it looks a little bit like auto-promotion, but we couldn’t do this article without including TeamMood – after all, we are a tool for wellbeing at work]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would you like to know your team members’ feelings and thoughts? Or to identify problems as they arise – and be able to handle them before they escalate? Or to get regular feedback and suggestions from your team members in order to continuously improve your organization?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=teammood_blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt; can do for you. Simply by sending a daily email to all of your team members, you can monitor their levels of happiness, collect their comments and be proactive should a problem arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=teammood_blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/8-tools/teammood.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Discover%20your%20team%20members%E2%80%99%20feelings%20and%20thoughts%20with%20@teammood%20%23wellbeingatwork%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html&quot;&gt;
    “Discover your team members’ feelings and thoughts with @teammood #wellbeingatwork”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hivy--brings-happiness-to-your-workplace&quot;&gt;Hivy – brings happiness to your workplace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do coffee, notepads and a ping-pong table have in common? The same person in your company is probably responsible for buying all of  them, along with all the other everyday purchases for the office. Gathering requests and placing orders can be quite tedious  for your office manager or personal assistant or whoever is charged with the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where Hivy comes in. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hivyapp.com/&quot;&gt;Hivy&lt;/a&gt; is an office management platform that creates a unique workplace experience. With a web and smartphone app or through a simple Slack command, all the wonderful people in your office can submit requests and make suggestions using Hivy. Office managers can handle their projects and manage the building within the app: get IT support, catering for an event, a cleaning company, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://hivyapp.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/8-tools/hivy.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with all the material and snacks they need/want, your team members can relax and focus on getting their work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Snacks,%20hoodies,%20IT%20support%E2%80%A6%20get%20everything%20you%20need%20for%20the%20office%20with%20@hivyapp%20%23wellbeingattheoffice%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html&quot;&gt;
    “Snacks, hoodies, IT support… get everything you need for the office with @hivyapp #wellbeingattheoffice”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;exclusive-briq--much-more-than-a-thank-you&quot;&gt;[Exclusive] Briq – much more than a thank you&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specialists have weighed in: wellbeing at work is strongly correlated with peer recognition, and even more so with personalized, public, and recurring recognition. But you can’t really orchestrate peer recognition within your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why the &lt;a href=&quot;https://efounders.co/&quot;&gt;eFounders&lt;/a&gt;’ team has created a peer recognition tool, Briq, that allows teammates to thank, to congratulate someone or to cheer someone up with a simple Slack command. The briqs you receive can be used through a set of applications: Bootiq, to buy goodies from the company shop (a company hoodie, a one-month, 6-month, or yearly subscription to Spotify or the gym, etc.), Snacky, to get a coffee or a snack, and much more. Employees can also receive briqs from the company itself, for instance when they share a corporate article on their personal social media, or when they refer someone for an open position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briq is conceived to adapt to each company’s needs and uses: you can personalize the applications and even build you own ones to incentivize actions that matter to your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.givebriq.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/8-tools/briq.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What started as an internal tool just turned into a project all of its own. Briq is still in private beta, but you can grab an invite here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givebriq.com/&quot;&gt;www.givebriq.com&lt;/a&gt;. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;inv-tweet-sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Say%20thank%20you%20and%20much%20more%20with%20%23Briq%20the%20last%20project%20by%20@efounders%20%23funatwork%20%23wellbeing%20%23peerrecognition%20https://blog.teammood.com/2017/05/23/8-exclusive-tools-to-make-your-teammates-happier-at-work.html&quot;&gt;
    “Say thank you and much more with #Briq the last project by @efounders #funatwork #wellbeing #peerrecognition”
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;sa-icon-twitter-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-turn&quot;&gt;Your turn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you, do you have other tools for wellbeing at the office you’d like to share? Feel free to tell us in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 14:25:54 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Warnings That a Crisis Is Looming Among Your Teammates.</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/04/11/8-warnings-that-a-crisis-is-looming-among-your-teammates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/04/11/8-warnings-that-a-crisis-is-looming-among-your-teammates.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My mum always told me: the most difficult thing about the workplace is not the work itself, but the relationships. Indeed, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://img.en25.com/Web/CPP/Conflict_report.pdf&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; conducted in 2008 in Europe, the US and Brazil, 85% of employees at all levels experience some degree of conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If conflict is not dealt with as it arises, months or years of tension and unspoken conflict will take a toll on teamwork, and can eventually degenerate into an open altercation. I have even witnessed a situation in which years of frustration, lack of understanding, and unspoken tension ended in moral harassment charges. &lt;strong&gt;Burying your head in the sand is never a solution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here are 8 signs of underlying conflict you should pay attention to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;underperforming-team-members&quot;&gt;1. Underperforming team members&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workgroup conflict is a huge demotivator: when people are not happy with the work environment, they tend to focus less on their work. If one or several team members are underperforming, being reluctant to do their job, or missing project deadlines, you can be sure that something is off in your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worse still, underperforming team members can aggravate  tension among your teammates. Indeed, if one of our peers is lagging  in terms of productivity and effort, we tend to feel resentful towards them and the manager who is failing to hold them accountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lateness-and-absenteeism&quot;&gt;2. Lateness and absenteeism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When there is conflict in the workplace, employees usually feel like being anywhere else. They tend to come in late, take long breaks to avoid getting back to work, and call in sick more than usual: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/207196&quot;&gt;25% of workers admit that conflict avoidance has led to their own absenteeism or illness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can be  late now and then. But if it becomes an everyday occurrence, then you should broach the subject with your teammate, and give  him or her the opportunity to explain. Beware though, this doesn’t apply to parents of newborn babies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abnormal-sick-leave&quot;&gt;3. Abnormal sick leave&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/sick-leave.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflict in the workplace is an huge source of stress. If left to fester, this stress can cause a variety of illnesses and medical conditions: increased rates of heart attack, hypertension, and even burnouts. Indeed, according to a study conducted among employees in North America in 2016, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/315848/employee-stress-sources-at-work-in-north-america/&quot;&gt;31 percent of respondents reported that work relationships were a source of stress&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dysfunctional-meetings&quot;&gt;4. Dysfunctional meetings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do staff meetings end up turning into gripe sessions instead of brainstorming sessions? Are there some people who always seem to dominate the conversation while others appear annoyed or distracted?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If team members are not showing up to meetings, if they are reluctant to participate, or if they display a critical, sceptical or sarcastic attitude during a meeting, consider this a red flag that something is going on in the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lack-of-cooperation-and-exclusion&quot;&gt;5. Lack of cooperation and exclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/exclusion.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teammates who are reluctant to work together are probably having some interpersonal problems. Conflict can even bring people together in factions against individuals they see as causing problems in the workplace. Behaviors such as sitting in cliques at coffee or lunch breaks, or ‘secretly’ arranging gatherings to which a few specific people are not invited, should warn the manager that something is off within the team and make him or her react quickly to avoid escalation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disrespect-and-gossip-in-the-workplace&quot;&gt;6. Disrespect and gossip in the workplace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intense conflict makes us see others as undeserving of our respect. Being rude to each other, rolling one’s eyes, and turning away while someone is speaking are signs that conflict is brewing. Likewise, gossip and criticism can only lead to animosity and should be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of behaviour is actually considered to be a  subtle form of harassment. It can lead to anger and fear among teammates, but management often doesn’t recognize it until pre-litigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;organizational-exodus-and-resignation&quot;&gt;7. Organizational exodus and resignation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If staff turnover is high, whether it be due to  resignation or transfer requests, you can bet that there is a reason. Over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/207196&quot;&gt;30% of workers state that interpersonal issues have led to someone leaving the organization&lt;/a&gt;. Don’t underestimate how costly employee turnover is for the organization. Given the cost of recruitment, including training a new employee, paying other employees involved in the hiring and training process, severance pay, and the loss of investment involved in losing an existing worker, replacing an employee actually costs  150 to 200 percent more than the original employee’s salary and benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formal-complaints&quot;&gt;8. Formal complaints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/formal-complaint.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If unresolved, conflict between employees can lead to workmates  filing complaints and holding grudges  against each other. And rest assured that investigations, disciplinary proceedings and adjudications don’t bring people together - they just drive people further apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve noticed some of these signs or not, you should always strive to keep the lines of communication open between you and your teammates and encourage them to come to you with  any difficulty they may encounter - personal and professional. Unaddressed conflict will always prove more  costly to the organization than a few hours spent trying to resolve it early on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next article, we will provide some of the solutions that can prevent or resolve a crisis in the workplace. &lt;strong&gt;Subscribe to our newsletter and receive the article directly in your inbox&lt;/strong&gt; (and only our articles).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 14:27:20 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wellbeing at Work: The Benefits of Happiness in the Workplace</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/en/2017/03/07/wellbeing-at-work-the-benefits-of-happiness-in-the-workplace.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The world has never before seen such high levels of productivity – even in France with our 5 weeks of vacation – and it is very much a consequence of the digital revolution and the automatization of many tasks. But the side effects of this faster work pace are not always welcome: burnout, depression, lack of purpose… Is being “sick on the job” the scourge of our age?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing’s for sure: a good paycheck is no longer enough to attract and retain the best talent. And companies know this: chief happiness officers, stress management coaches, and wellbeing programs are emerging to improve happiness in the workplace. So, what is actually at stake?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;happiness-at-work-the-key-to-increased-productivity&quot;&gt;Happiness at work, the key to increased productivity?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers from the University of Warwick in the UK have actually validated the theory. In 2014, Pr. Andrew J. Oswald, Pr. Eugenio Proto, and Pr. Daniel Sgroi published the striking results of their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.warwick.ac.uk/fac/soc/economics/staff/eproto/workingpapers/happinessproductivity.pdf&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;happy people were found to be 12% more productive, while unhappy workers proved 10% less productive.&lt;/strong&gt; According to the three economists, “human happiness has large and positive causal effects on productivity. Positive emotions appear to invigorate human beings.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is true for individuals is all the more true for organizations. Companies that invest in employee support and satisfaction tend to succeed in fostering happier workers. And happy workers tend to work better with others, to have more energy, to be more creative, to fix problems instead of complaining about them, and to make better decisions overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proof is in the profit. In 2005, Jerome Dodson, the founder of Parnassus Investments, added a new branch to his activities: the Parnassus Workplace Fund, a mutual fund that invests exclusively in large American firms proven to have &lt;strong&gt;outstanding workplaces, where employees are really happy.&lt;/strong&gt; The kinds of firms that “genuinely cared about their employees as people, not just hired hands.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dodson scouted the country, not for the most promising companies, but for the companies that treated employees with profound respect and offered them ongoing training and personal development. Other criteria included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Providing a meaningful form of profit sharing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Offering healthcare and retirement benefits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being supportive of working mothers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happiness pays!&lt;/strong&gt; To Dodson’s delight, the Parnassus Workplace Fund proved immediately, enormously, and enduringly successful. Since the fund’s inception and for 8 years, it “has had returns over 4% better than the S&amp;amp;P Index every year.” I’m sure we’d all like to get the same yield!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(For those of you who are not familiar with market valuations, the Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s 500, is an American stock market index based on the market capitalizations of 500 large companies with common stock listed on the NYSE or NASDAQ. Now you know.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when the latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gallup.com/poll/165269/worldwide-employees-engaged-work.aspx&quot;&gt;Gallup&lt;/a&gt; study tells you that “only 13 percent of employees are engaged at work worldwide” it makes you wonder &lt;strong&gt;why happiness in the workplace isn’t a higher priority.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-you-boost-wellbeing-at-work&quot;&gt;How do you boost wellbeing at work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/building-joy-planning-plans.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sharing those results, you must be wondering: how can I boost employee engagement and happiness in my company?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there’s good news and bad news. The bad news is: you cannot impose happiness on your employees. They have their share of responsibility in their own happiness. However, you can still set up ground rules and working conditions that will help your employees and teammates blossom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;develop-a-culture-of-trust-and-transparency&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Develop a culture of trust and transparency…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… where your employees can share their doubts and flaws, ask questions, challenge one another.. Keeping people afraid of failing or of showing weakness is the best way to hinder creativity. Your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;show-gratitude-and-value-positive-intelligence&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Show gratitude and value positive intelligence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead by example. To set up a culture of gratitude and kindness, just display these qualities. If you are convincing enough, your teammates will follow your lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;foster-empowerment-and-accountability&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foster empowerment and accountability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stay engaged, a worker needs to feel that his job matters, and to be recognized for it. Empowering each individual to carry out his or her own tasks, and praising the results is the best way &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.teammood.com/engagement/tips/2013/07/30/how-to-improve-the-employee-engagement-with-these-5-great-tips.html&quot;&gt;to boost employee engagement&lt;/a&gt; – which doesn’t mean disparaging them should they need help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;favor-breaks-and-downtime&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favor breaks and downtime&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to what most people may think, procrastination is actually good for productivity. While at ease, our brain enters its default mode and starts processing and sorting out information. These default mode phases are essential to our brain. Promoting &lt;strong&gt;breaks and relaxation will boost your teammates’ productivity and creativity.&lt;/strong&gt; It will also lower stress and frustration. Once again, I’d advise you to lead by example. Take a real lunch break and invite your teammates to join you. Take the time for coffee breaks and talk about anything but work. You can even set up a space to meditate, nap or do some yoga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;launch-a-wellness-program&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Launch a wellness program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set up a healthy lunch or snacks program, sponsor gym membership, dedicate a room to yoga or fitness… Did you know that exercise actually stimulates endorphins (endorphins are neurotransmitters that induce a feeling of euphoria) (what better way to get happy?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s your turn to be creative. What are your top tips for improving well being at your workplace?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 09:33:53 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MoraleApp Is Shutting Down :-(</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/en/2016/10/05/moraleapp-is-shutting-down.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/en/2016/10/05/moraleapp-is-shutting-down.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 5th 2016, &lt;a href=&quot;https://moraleapp.com/shutdown&quot;&gt;MoraleApp announced that they are shutting down their service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a sad news for their users that have to look for an alternative but also for TeamMood who lose a pretty great competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, TeamMood has worked hard and it is now possible to migrate from MoraleApp to TeamMood seamlessly, without loosing your historical data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to import your MoraleApp data into TeamMood, just register there: 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getdrip.com/forms/14519314/submissions/new&quot;&gt;https://www.getdrip.com/forms/14519314/submissions/new&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 21:14:13 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 (Easy) Ways to Boost Team Productivity!</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/en/2016/01/12/5-ways-to-boost-team-productivity.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/en/2016/01/12/5-ways-to-boost-team-productivity.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As studies have shown time and time again, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.warwick.ac.uk/newsandevents/pressreleases/new_study_shows/&quot;&gt;happy teams are productive teams&lt;/a&gt;. So if you want to boost your team’s productivity, team happiness is definitely one of the goals that you should be setting yourself. It’s not just a matter of teamwork. When people are happy­ they work better and faster, whether as a team &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.inc.com/jessica-stillman/happiness-makes-your-brain-work-better.html&quot;&gt;or as individuals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now you know how to boost your team’s productivity. Make them happy. How do you make them happy? Here are a few ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;daily-meetings-contribute-to-wellbeing-at-work&quot;&gt;#1. Daily meetings contribute to wellbeing at work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily meetings (short daily meetings of course) are an excellent way to start off the day, and give your team a sense of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These meetings should be open to all, meaning that any team member can speak their mind and offer their own opinion. They can bring their own ideas to the table, and feel that they have a real and tangible contribution to the team’s work, and the company’s success as a whole. When people are ‘engaged’ like this in the company’s decisions, they are more dedicated, and yes, happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/daily_meeting.png&quot; alt=&quot;Daily meeting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, you can also have these meetups in the middle of the day, as that creates a nice little break for your team, and they can have a breather before going on with the rest of their day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;track-their-mood&quot;&gt;#2. Track their mood&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you should be aware of your team as individuals, tracking the mood of the entire team is invaluable. Of course if you see that one of your team members isn’t happy you should have a talk with them, and see if you can help them resolve any issues that they may be having, but being able to judge the overall mood of the team is an excellent way to head off any problems that might happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=5-easy-ways-to-boost-team-productivity&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_5-easy-ways-to-boost-team-productivity&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/teammood-main-en.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Track the mood&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, if people are becoming unhappy simply because they don’t have a coffee machine (and yes, we’ve seen that happen ☺), recognizing the fact that this is causing the entire team to underperform helps find a solution. In this case, it’s easy (just buy a coffee machine), but still – tracking the team’s mood is what helped find the underlying cause of the unhappiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wanna try to follow the mood of your people, we have you covered with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=5-easy-ways-to-boost-team-productivity&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_5-easy-ways-to-boost-team-productivity&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;positive-feedback&quot;&gt;#3. Positive feedback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want your team members to be happy and improve their wellbeing at work? Tell them you appreciate them! It is literally as simple as that. It’s amazing at how a few simple compliments – when deserved – will brighten someone’s day up, and turn them into a far happier (and productive) person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;show-how-to-prioritize&quot;&gt;#4. Show how to prioritize&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter if it’s the developers launching the product on time, the Sales team meeting their quota, or the IT guys getting through all their helpdesk tickets - Getting work done contributes to the team happiness. You can’t always do EVERYTHING, of course, but you can certainly get the most urgent stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/priority.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Prioritiez&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how does the team to that? By prioritizing. But how does your team know what to prioritize? Is the login feature more important than the Facebook share feature? Is the negotiation with ACME company more important than finding a connection to &lt;a href=&quot;http://seinfeld.wikia.com/wiki/Vandelay_Industries&quot;&gt;Vandelay Industries&lt;/a&gt;? That’s where you come in. As the team manager, it’s your job to help the team understand what is more important, so they can start clearing the workload off their desks, and yes, feel more accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;delegation&quot;&gt;#5. Delegation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful teamwork – and one of the keys to happy teams – is delegation. You can’t do everything yourself, and you shouldn’t have to. Share responsibilities with your key workers, give tasks to individuals and share the workload in general with your team, and not only will it be easier for you to get your job done, they will feel more appreciated and trusted. And team members that feel like the team leader trusts them­ will try harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, you see that making people feeling better at the workplace can be pretty easily done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 12:33:11 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Les Facteurs Qui Influent Sur L’humeur Au Travail</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/fr/2015/10/15/les-facteurs-qui-influent-sur-lhumeur-au-travail.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/fr/2015/10/15/les-facteurs-qui-influent-sur-lhumeur-au-travail.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Adopter la positive attitude au bureau n’est pas toujours facile. À force de côtoyer les mêmes personnes dans les mêmes bureaux toute la semaine, on finit par voir les sourires disparaître sur les visages. La courbe de notre humeur vacille sans vraiment que nous en comprenions les raisons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quels sont les facteurs qui rentrent en compte dans notre humeur ? Comment cultiver la bonne humeur au travail ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lenvironnement-de-travail&quot;&gt;L’environnement de travail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L’environnement de travail est l’un des points les plus importants. Si vous êtes au bureau, regardez autour de vous. Votre espace de travail vous permet-il de travailler dans de bonnes conditions ? Avez-vous assez d’espace ? Êtes-vous installé confortablement ? Le niveau sonore n’est-il pas trop élevé ? La luminosité est-elle suffisante ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tous ces éléments mis bout à bout contribuent à votre bien-être, et donc votre bonne humeur au travail. Saviez-vous que la lumière vous met de bonne humeur et vous rend plus efficace au travail ? À contrario, le manque de lumière va vous faire sécréter en quantité trop importante l’hormone du sommeil : la mélatonine. Vous perdrez alors toute votre énergie et n’aurez qu’une seule envie… celle de rentrer chez vous et de dormir ! Les bienfaits de la lumière sont prouvés scientifiquement : pour lutter contre les dépressions saisonnières les médecins recommandent la luminothérapie. Cette thérapie par la lumière consiste à s’exposer quotidiennement à une lumière artificielle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/people-office-group-team.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Environnement de travail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vous savez ce qu’il vous reste à faire : faire vos pauses à l’extérieur pour faire le plein de lumière naturelle et vous équiper de lampes de bureau si l’éclairage est insuffisant !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Que ce soit par manque de lumière, d’espace ou de confort vous avez mille et une raisons de vous sentir mal au bureau. Ne restez pas frustré si vous pensez pouvoir être mieux installé que vous l’êtes actuellement ! Faites remonter vos remarques et suggestions à votre supérieur, abordez le problème en réunion ou prenez des initiatives si les choses ne changent pas ! Vos collègues, qui sont sûrement du même avis que vous, vous remercieront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lattitude-vis--vis-de-vos-collgues&quot;&gt;L’attitude vis à vis de vos collègues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dire bonjour au bureau : un geste anodin mais qui toutefois permet de débuter la journée sur une note positive ! Si ce n’est déjà le cas, n’hésitez pas à parcourir tous les bureaux pour prendre le temps de saluer vos collègues un à un.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Quoi de plus énervant que de se faire couper la parole ou de voir des collègues concentrés sur leur smartphone au moment où vous prenez la parole en réunion ? Soyez vous-même exemplaire : n’envoyez pas de texto en réunion, sentez-vous impliqué par ce qui est en train de se passer. Des règles élémentaires certes, mais qu’il n’est pas inutile de rappeler…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Aidez vos collègues : n’hésitez pas à rendre un coup de pouce à vos collègues et à vous entraider. Ils vous le rendront bien le jour où vous aurez besoin d’eux. Vous tisserez ainsi des liens avec vos collègues en partageant ces moments un peu informels.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Prenez le temps pour déjeuner avec vos collègues. Vous avez la manie de déjeuner derrière votre écran ou d’avaler un sandwich en cinq minutes entre deux rendez-vous ?  Vous devriez arrêter ! Il est prouvé que les déjeuners pris ensemble permettent de souder les équipes ! Ce sont des moments privilégiés pour échanger avec vos collègues autour de sujets autre que le travail (sisi, on vous promet ça fait du bien de temps en temps !)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/people-coffee-tea-meeting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Collaboration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;soyez-vous-mme-positif&quot;&gt;Soyez vous-même positif&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Un problème de transport, une météo déplorable… de quoi vous mettre en rogne ! Même si de nombreux facteurs externes jouent sur votre humeur vous êtes le seul maître de votre humeur. Vous ne devez pas céder à l’envie de râler à tout bout de champ dès que quelque chose ne va pas. En vous plaignant, vos collègues ressentent de l’empathie pour vous et s’imaginent à votre place. De ce fait, ils se sentent mal à leur tour. Attention donc à ne pas plomber l’ambiance générale avec vos soucis quotidiens.
Si vous ne dégagez pas quelque chose de positif, vos collègues vous fuiront et voudront passer le moins de temps possible à vos côtés. En râlant, c’est aussi sur votre propre moral que vous agissez.  En étant positif vous vous entourerez de personnes elles-mêmes positives : un vrai cercle vertueux !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bref&quot;&gt;Bref…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La bonne humeur au travail est avant tout un état d’esprit auquel chacun d’entre nous doit s’exercer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tous les chefs d’entreprise aspirent à une ambiance générale qui puisse satisfaire ceux qui travaillent dans l’entreprise afin d’éviter des démissions trop régulières liées à une mauvaise ambiance. Ces démissions pourraient être néfastes pour l’entreprise à long terme : elles sont un vrai gouffre financier pour l’entreprise qui doit continuellement recruter et former de nouveaux salariés. Autant d’argent qui aurait pu être investi pour améliorer le bien-être des salariés.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultiver la bonne humeur au travail : vous avez tout à y gagner !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 11:35:51 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TeamMood Now On Your Wall</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/features/tips/2015/07/30/teammood-now-on-your-wall.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/features/tips/2015/07/30/teammood-now-on-your-wall.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/dashboard_monitor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard Monitor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to contributions from some of our power users (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nrichand&quot;&gt;Nathaniel Richand&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/guillaume_patry&quot;&gt;Guillaume Patry&lt;/a&gt;), it is now possible to display the latest moods of your team on your monitoring display in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They wrote widgets for &lt;a href=&quot;http://dashing.io/&quot;&gt;Dashing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Smashing/smashing&quot;&gt;Smashing&lt;/a&gt;, a great and easy to use free dashboard frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TeamMood widgets look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/teammood_widget.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dashing TeamMood Widget (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/nrichand/265342903eabc4ad0050&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/teammood_smashing_widget.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Smashing TeamMood Widget (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gpatry/Smashing-SparklineMood&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use them and don’t forget to send us pictures ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 15:47:39 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Effectively Remove Google Analytics Spam</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/tech/2014/12/13/how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/tech/2014/12/13/how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since several months, you certainly have seen some strange referral sources in your Google Analytics reports. Those are spam:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/spam.png&quot; alt=&quot;Spam in Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have several ways to avoid this, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;using segment by excluding these domains in Google Analytics reports&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;excluding these domains in Google Analytics filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you have to know which domains to exclude for both methods, and they are evolving everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most effective way I found is to only include traffic that go to your website (the spam does not really go on your website, they just mess with the Google Analytics API).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that, just go to the Google Analytics Admin Panel, and choose “Filter”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/ga_admin.png&quot; alt=&quot;Filters in Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then add a new filter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/ga_filters.png&quot; alt=&quot;Add a new filter in Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the last steps are to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;choose a name for your filter, such as “Exclude Spam”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;select “Custom”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;click “Include”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;choose “Hostname” in the “Filter field”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in the “Filter Pattern” field, use the following syntax &lt;code&gt;.*teammood.com| translate.googleusercontent.com&lt;/code&gt; and replace &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam&quot;&gt;teammood.com&lt;/a&gt; by your domain name (Google Translate is there in case people are using it to translate your page with Chrome).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/ga_remove_spam.png&quot; alt=&quot;Remove Spam in Google Analytics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will not remove the old spam, but from now, the spam will not ever be recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this tip made your day? If so, take a look at how TeamMood is helping teams to have better days :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://www.teammood.com/?utm_source=blog&amp;amp;utm_medium=post&amp;amp;utm_content=how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog_how-to-effectively-remove-google-analytics-spam&quot;&gt;Discover TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 07:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Employee Recognition in the Workplace</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/recognition/workplace/tips/2013/10/22/the-importance-of-employee-recognition-in-the-workplace.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/recognition/workplace/tips/2013/10/22/the-importance-of-employee-recognition-in-the-workplace.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Canadian HR Council&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, employee recognition is the “the acknowledgement of an individual or team’s behavior, effort and accomplishments that support the organization’s goals and values.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee recognition usually takes a couple of forms, either informal or formal. Informal recognition is very spontaneous and helps encouraging certain behaviors that you want to reinforce in the workplace. On the other hand, formal recognition takes place when employees or departments are rewarded for exceeding strategic goals and objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these can be instrumental in establishing a positive and supportive climate within your company. Let’s look at three reasons why every manager should adopt an employee recognition program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increase-employee-productivity-companywide&quot;&gt;Increase employee productivity companywide&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By recognizing their good work, employees will be motivated to go above and beyond their call of duty. It drives them to outperform themselves, and always become better at what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees who are constantly reminded that they are doing an extraordinary job also feel like they are participating in the overall success of your company. Therefore, they become intrinsically motivated about their job, which is proven to have a positive impact on their productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A side benefit of employee recognition is that it dramatically increases employee competitiveness. When their colleagues are rewarded for their achievements, employees are likely to try harder and achieve even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;helps-retain-and-attract-talented-employees&quot;&gt;Helps retain and attract talented employees&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee recognition programs can have a positive impact on turnover rates. Indeed, this human resources management tool is one of the best ways to retain existing employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stress in the workplace is extremely counterproductive, and encouraging your employees can help relieve it. In the short term, absenteeism will be reduced. In the long run, employment longevity will be maximized, therefore reducing expensive turnover costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, employee recognition will attract talented employees to work for your company. Many job seekers are attracted to companies that are ranked as some of the best places to work for. For example, Glassdoor&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; makes it incredibly easy for existing and former employees to review your firm—and they can potentially make or break your reputation as an employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;increase-revenues-and-maximize-profitability&quot;&gt;Increase revenues and maximize profitability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It goes without saying that employee recognition will have a positive impact on your bottom line. Despite the time and effort put into an effective employee recognition program, the investment is unquestionably worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees who are intrinsically motivated by their job will achieve more in a shorter amount of time. Teamwork will be enhanced within and across departments. By establishing the right culture, employees will be inclined to share their innovative ideas to improve a particular process or create a brand new product. The possibilities are endless, and the upside potential for your bottom line is unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the importance of employee recognition, one must understand the psychology behind it. Whichever their level in the organizational chart, people like to be valued for their contribution. One of the components of an amazing workplace is the gratitude towards every single employee. Unfortunately, appreciation is often undervalued in organizations of all sizes. However, as one of the most powerful management technique, employee recognition should be a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hrcouncil.ca/hr-toolkit/keeping-people-employee-recognition.cfm&quot;&gt;http://hrcouncil.ca/hr-toolkit/keeping-people-employee-recognition.cfm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glassdoor.com/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.glassdoor.com/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Improve the Employee Engagement With These 5 Great Tips</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/engagement/tips/2013/07/30/how-to-improve-the-employee-engagement-with-these-5-great-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/engagement/tips/2013/07/30/how-to-improve-the-employee-engagement-with-these-5-great-tips.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Each company works hard towards improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time pass by, business keeps on improving and keeps on growing which opens great chances of hiring people. These people will play a big role for the growth of the business. Being an employee, you must possess a qualification that each company requires. You must be a happy people, willing to do the work, begin the engagement as an action not as survey, and you must know how to engage yourself from the bottom and not to the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we say employee engagement, these are managing people who are fully involved in a company who are being very enthusiastic about their work. They care about the future of the company they are working for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-how-bosses-really-enhance-employee-engagement&quot;&gt;But how bosses really enhance employee engagement?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts with the leaders or the founders of the company. Since they are the head of the company, they should help their employees to learn how to be engaged in their work. They must show that they value their employees. They should provide challenging work with career advancement and communicate clear vision to the employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognition&lt;/strong&gt; to the job well done is big help. In many companies, recognition and financial rewards are joined at hip. By means of this, employees become more motivated to do their work and become more productive. Recognition is a key tool to make your employee opt for extra effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autonomy&lt;/strong&gt; at work helps the employee to set their own schedules. They have the right to decide how they are going to do their work. Using these methods helps employee to become more productive and happier at work. Having this option helps them to fulfill the work because they have freedom to make decision. Employers give parameters and suggest choices. This make the employee give a dedicated level of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Company employee also needs respect. &lt;strong&gt;Respect&lt;/strong&gt; is a form of showing a regards or concern to the workers. Treating the employee with right attitude is good to help them feel that they belong in the company they are working for. Managers can show respect by means of several ways such as dealing with people with courtesy and kindness, encourage to express opinion and ideas, and never insult people in front of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why is it that employees need to be engaged at work? There is a good objective that the team wants to achieve. &lt;strong&gt;Pointing out your purpose&lt;/strong&gt; help you find out why. Maybe you want to become more successful, you want to inspire your family or you want to bring hopes in your community; these things will help you to have your own purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a &lt;strong&gt;good facilitator&lt;/strong&gt; in managing a company is also a scalable approach to making every detail of the task well streamlined thus maximizing efficiency and resolving conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the tips above will help you become a good example. At the same time, it will create a better result of being productive at work. Above all, dedication and strategic management are keys to reach success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 17:43:42 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Build your own niko-niko calendar</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/diy/2013/05/07/build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/diy/2013/05/07/build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you know what is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.teammood.com/blog/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko/&quot;&gt;Niko-Niko practice&lt;/a&gt;, it is now time to build your own !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;materials&quot;&gt;Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The calendar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some stickers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A piece of paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can print some monthly calendars using this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vertex42.com/calendars/printable-calendars.html&quot;&gt;free service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vertex42.com/calendars/printable-calendars.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/printable-calendar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Printable calendar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, buy some stickers, take these ones for instance, which are available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Color-Coding-Labels-Inches-Stickers/dp/B00DRGXBIM/&quot;&gt;Amazon US&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;center&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/stickers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stickers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-build-it-&quot;&gt;Let’s build it !&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the piece of paper, put the stickers with their meaning, for example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;green: happy day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;yellow: good day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;orange:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;red / pink: hard day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just pin the calendar, with the stickers and the piece of paper at the exit of the team room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-now-&quot;&gt;And now ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let each team member put a sticker on the calendar at the end of each working day, and voila !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you’re too busy to build your own, take a look at our service : &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com/?utm_source=Build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog-Build-your-own-niko-niko-calendar&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;, an easy way to get a glimpse of the happiness of your coworkers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 14:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is the niko-niko ?</title>
        <link>http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/faq/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.teammood.com/niko-niko/faq/2013/04/21/what-is-the-niko-niko.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko calendar is an Agile practice which aims to detect patterns of change of mood of a team over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;/images/posts/niko-niko.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;An example of Niko-niko calendar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technic is very easy: at the end of the day, each team member paste a sticker on a calendar to tell if he had a good day at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--More--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other word, you probably ever went back to home from work and feel that you had a bad day, or you did not feel “productive”. That’s a red sticker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time, you’ll see some color being dominant, it will give an insight of the mood of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a good idea to take a look at the Niko-niko calendar during the Agile retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not exact science, it is just a simple tool to get some more informations about the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Niko-niko calendar is also know as “happiness index”. Also note that “niko” means “smile” in the japanese language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first mention of the Niko-niko calendar is from an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geocities.jp/nikonikocalendar/index_en.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article from Akinori SAKATA in 2006&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now, if you work with remote teams, and if it is not possible to use a physical calendar in the room, take a look at our service : &lt;a href=&quot;http://teammood.com/?utm_source=what-is-niko-niko&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=blog-what-is-niko-niko &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;TeamMood&lt;/a&gt;, an easy way to get a glimpse of the happiness of your coworkers !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 21:57:00 +0200</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
